[music]
Heat. Hey. Hey. Hey. [music]
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hey,
hey, hey. [music]
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hello, good evening everybody and good
day to you as well. And those of you who
are watching in the daytime, I hope
everyone is great and welcome to the Ask
Abijit Show episode 305. Today we
discuss the most dangerous thing we can
discuss on this channel which is
geopolitics and I'm going to take
questions from the super chat and the
live chat. Before we do that, let's see
who all we have on the live stream. I
can see Nagendra, Adiga, Sorab, RPPL,
it's 9:30 a.m. in Washington where RPPL
is. Well, good to have you, sir. Chat
DSP,
good to see you. DSP U Duta Alvin
Rodriguez says maths and science is
beautiful. It is it is no question about
that. Dak says Ram Ram Avin Kumar
Kanesh Koshik good day good evening
nabani Tadas good to see you as well Mr.
Jam Kdar Pab You
Shiva Kapoor Chad DSP Jay Desai Ken What
do I think about Trump and Bill Clinton?
What can I say? Silent viewer. Hello.
Abishek Shukla is here from Kpur. Good
to have you sir. Nabar Tadas Shou
nationalist.
Uh Swami Jane is here from Jaipur.
Geopolitical. Good evening from Indor.
Uh Hitan Shua is here from Gujarat. Somi
Jane Abishek Shukla
Bharata Patriotic Sager Torat Namaskarum
Bruce Wayne good to have you shub
nationalist mystic skai
critical thinker um Ashwani good evening
pranav Sharma is here from Jammu Ashish
Tripati from Gorakpur hello Mr. Sakenna
is here from Dublin in Ireland. Shashir
Upad here. Yu Yu Yuyu youu Amisha Mishra
is also here. Good evening ma'am. Super
papy111. Om nik from Chhattisgarh. Sorab
is here from Canada.
Um Mcloven is here. Super PAP 1111.
Uh Ashmani Sab Mahajan Rudra Shakall 108
Shivo Shivohham from Canada. Harley
Diddison. [laughter]
Okay. Uh Ashishati Shreas Mitra is here
from Moscow. Moscow good evening I
suppose in Moscow. Ambikari 52 good to
have you ma'am once again. Freedom from
outcome is here from Canada. Uh Lion Leo
is here from China. Well Niha Mr.
Namaste namaste Kiran Krishna hello
satellite Ashwani Ara Prab Banerjee. Uh
anonymous scientist Mo good doing great.
Satellite has become a new member. Thank
you so much and let us all welcome
satellite to the membership of the
channel. Thank you very much indeed.
Malik Patel is here from Gujarat. Malik
Patel. Well, okay. Um and everyone else.
Okay. I will not be able to greet all of
you individually. B is here. Ansley
Franco is also here. Uh Sunil Kumar is
here from Hunasi Karnataka. Anandu MS.
Han Krishna Kumar from Kerala. Big
beautiful bill. Okay. Swami Chen. All
right. Okay. Let's take some questions,
shall we? Let's take some questions.
I'll take as many as possible over the
next couple of hours. So, let's see.
Rudi says, "Why you and we subs can't
start a deep state?" Seriously. Okay.
[snorts]
Let's say we all start a deep state.
What will we
seek to achieve with that? What is the
actual deep state? Right? You want to
start a deep state because the Americans
allegedly have a deep state. Well, let's
understand the characteristics of the US
deep states. Deep state who are the
members of the deep state. Do we know?
No. They are hidden away. They are
anonymous. That's number one. We if we
start a deep state, we will be known.
Number two, the the members of the
alleged American deep state, they are
the most powerful people in the world.
They control heads of state. They
control nations. They control entire
economies. They control a significant
portion of the world's economy.
Will we be in a position to do that? So
the point is if you start something you
need to have clear defined objectives.
You can't just say okay let's start a
cha chacha group and name it deep state
and we feel good about that. It doesn't
work like that right? So if you want to
start something like that you have to
first of all place yourself in a
position where you are super powerful
and super wealthy and then you have to
find like-minded people who are similar
to you. super powerful, super wealthy,
and then you start a deep state quietly
without any without any fanfare. That's
how you start a deep state. Okay? You
have to first of all be extremely
wealthy and extremely powerful. I'm
talking about hundreds of billions of
dollars wealthy. I'm not sure I have
that much money [laughter]
as of now. Right? So, that's the deal.
Okay. Minimalist Maverick says, "Why the
US wants to destroy India? Why can't we
all India, US, uh, Deutseland of France,
Great Great Great Britain? Why can't we
all be friends against China, Russia,
KP? Um, okay. KP, uh, will left and
right-wing political parties balconize
the US? My question is, why do we have
to stand against Russia? Why should
India be an enemy of Russia? Why do
India Why does India need to be friends
with Great Britain,
the United States against
Russia? Forget about China. China, we
understand China has placed us in a
position where we have to be wary of
them. But why Russia? What has Russia
done to us? Russia, I don't see them
having done anything significant that
that hurts us or has has hurt us in the
past. What about the UK? Has the UK
behaved in a way that we can trust them
as friends? The UK destroyed our
civilization. They destroyed our economy
and you want to be friends with them.
So, is everything all right with you?
Why on earth would I be want to be
friends with this genocidal, barbaric,
monstrous nation called the UK and its
successor state, the United States,
which has funded and financed Pakistani
terrorism against us for decades. Why
would I want to be friends with them? I
don't want to be their enemy. But why
should we seek to be their friends? Can
we trust them? The first principle of
friendship is that you have to be able
to trust each other.
Do you understand what I'm trying to say
here? Do you see where I'm going?
Doesn't work that way. Why would we why
would we want to alienate Russia and
make make Russia our enemy? Why?
I don't get it. [snorts]
Okay. Next. Subramanyam Vishwanatan is a
new member. Thank you so much, sir.
Thank you so much. And let us all
welcome Subramanyam Vishnuatan G. Thank
you so much.
Basar Kayatwal says, "It was a great
pleasure meeting you in JD." Well,
likewise. It was great to meet you.
Could you please outline how the alleged
drug trade in South America is funded
abed by the by America themselves and
what purpose does it serve?
Um look we don't have any evidence but
we have
well circumstantial evidence let's say
which is not direct evidence so you
can't prove a thing right but let's look
at it this way
from the 1980s onwards
when I was a little kid I've been
hearing about the American war on drugs
Ronald Reagan
he goes on live television with his uh
first lady with his wife Nancy Nancy
Reagan and they talk about drugs, how
bad drugs are. Don't do drugs. Drugs are
evil. The US will launch a war on drugs.
Operation Condor, if anyone even
remembers what that was, Operation
Condor and and so much more. So, they
allegedly fought this war on drugs, the
United States, right? And the drugs were
apparently coming from certain parts of
the world such as uh the various cartels
in Central and South America. The
Mexican cartels, the Colombian cartels,
the lawa cartel, the Kali cartel, the
Median cartel and so so on so forth. And
there were very major players who used
to you know funnel drugs into the United
States. They had trade routes. You had
people like Carlos Leair who was the
pilot and there was a whole story about
him that I read as as a teenager. And
then there was obviously people like
Pablo Escobar, Cenor, Plata Oplammo,
that guy and of course there's the
golden triangle right next door to us
which is now intruding into India's own
territory and so on. So you have the
cartels in South America, Central
America who produce a tremendous amount
of product, let's call it, white powder
of various kinds. And where does it end
up? It ends up in the United States.
Apparently, the US has the best law
enforcement mechanisms in the world, the
best uh um you know, immigration
control, all of that. And yet, all of
this product ends up in in the United
States on the streets of the US. And if
you are a US citizen, you will have done
drugs at some point in your life.
If you are a kid in the US, 12 years
old, 15 years old, whatever, you have
access to drugs on every street corner.
So if the US is so anti-drugs, then why
are drugs so readily available? Just
like you can buy candy, you can buy
drugs in the US. Everybody has access to
drugs, right? Everyone knows the local
dealers.
Isn't this incredibly strange?
Doesn't this point to incredible
corruption in the United States? Is it
possible to have drugs supplied to each
street corner all across this gigantic
nation without the complicity of various
um
agencies,
politicians,
cops? Is it possible? Is it even
possible? Right? It's not. So, it looks
like
there's some kind of understanding, you
know, it looks like that. I may be
completely wrong. Of course, because we
don't have any evidence. Looks like
though there is somebody who is
producing a product. There's somebody
who is the consumer and there is clear
distribution. So there we have it. Now
why would let's say if this is allegedly
true hypothetically that the Americans
are you know allowing the cartels to
supply drugs into their country, why
would they do that? The cartels,
they become super powerful as a
consequence, right? Super powerful,
super wealthy. They have access to the
latest weaponry and whatnot. They are
like armies unto themselves. They are
like governments unto themselves. What
is the point of doing this? Well, one of
the ways this makes sense potentially is
that you use the cartels to control the
governments.
If the government gets out of hand and
they start enacting policies that are
counter that are counter that are
against the interest of the United
States, maybe you can use the cartels
to counterbalance the governments. The
cartels are very nasty organizations,
very violent.
When there's a election, let's say in
Mexico, you'll find every election
election cycle several dozen politicians
are taken out. Bang bang, right?
Isn't this this a way of keeping each
country country country country country
under control
right? So think about it in in in these
ways. I'm not saying it's true. We have
no actual evidence but you know makes
sense logically this way. You need
leverage. Here's leverage. You keep
these cartels super powerful, super
wealthy, supplied with the latest arms
ammunition. You want them in your
pockets. you allow them to do certain
things and that way they get the money
and that way they work for you in their
in their respective countries. Well,
there we have it. That's all
hypothetical. Of course, there's no
evidence to to uh support what I'm
saying, but the cartels do exist and we
know where the product goes. So, there
is some let's say circumstantial
evidence but no direct evidence. Baskar
Kayatwal says if in the long term
Pakistan is starved of water due to the
indust water treaty obeyance inaction
hypothetically if some of their mass
population just starts walking towards
Rajasthan Punjab how does a nation
handle such a situation you put your
armed forces on on the border you have
fencing which already exists you have
armed forces you have tanks
those Pakistani zombies who will walk
towards your border they can be stopped
dead that's how you Um [clears throat]
that's how you hypothetically handle the
situation. There are laws in our
country. If you are a foreign national,
if you want to come into if you want to
enter our nation, you have to come
through the proper channels. You have to
apply for a visa. You have to wait for
us to process your application and
depending on how we [clears throat] you
see the merits and demerits of your
case, we may issue a visa or not. And if
you bypass that process and you try to
enter the country illegally,
right, you're committing the gravest of
crimes and we will take you out because
[clears throat] if you're coming in from
Pakistan illegally, you are most likely
going to be a terrorist. So it is
completely legal for us for our
government and our armed forces to take
you out if you're a Pakistani trying to
cross into our territory illegally. So
that's what we do.
Easy peasy. Even if a million of them
come, we can deal with them. No problem
at all. Right? We have satellites that
can monitor what's happening. We have
various other means of monitoring
exactly what's happening uh on on the
western side of the border, right? Or
the line of control. So no issue, easy
to deal with.
Critical thinker says a few of us after
a blast Islamabad blast happened looks
like engineered blast from Pakistan
government to play victim card again so
India doesn't retaliate is this new
normal now is is this is this an
intelligence failure from the government
okay
let's take the second part of the
question first is this an intelligence
failure from the government if you go
fishing
if you are in you know if you are fond
of fishing you'll go to river or the
lake or the sea or whatever. You'll put
out your fishing line and you'll wait
for the fish to catch catch your bait.
Now, tell me something. Is it possible
to catch every fish? It's not. Even if
you are not using, you know, the the the
rope and bait, if you're using a net,
even then you can't catch all the fish.
You the only way to catch all the fish
in a pond is to dynamite the pond or to
electrocute the pond, which is extremely
barbaric, right? No one wants to do
that. So the point is it's not possible
to catch all the fish when you have a
nation like ours with 1.4 billion people
and you have a 100 million potentially
Bangladeshes in the country. God knows
how many Rohhingas, God knows how many
what else we have
and also god knows how many Pakistanis
we have you know hidden among our
people.
It's it's going to be a huge problem for
us.
And the the fact is that the agencies,
the government agencies have have
uncovered this plot. They have been able
to capture confiscate several thousand
kilos apparently of uh you know
high-grade explosives, ammonium nitrate
and whatnot. and also several I don't
know sufficient uh rice in
which was enough to to kill hundreds of
thousands of people. So the government
agencies are are doing a great job and
apparently this bomb blast that happened
in Delhi near the red fort it was not
supposed to happen. They were
transporting they were in the process of
getting caught. They were trying to
escape and they were transporting um
apparently uh the explosive material
from one place to another and it blew up
on the way apparently because when
somebody blows up a car bomb let's say
in a crowded area you always will find
certain characteristics of that blast
the number one characteristic is that
that blast that explosive is going to
have a lot of nuts and bolts and nails
surrounding it so that when the
explosion happens
those nuts, bolts, and nails. They fly
out like bullets and cause tremendous
damage far from the actual place where
the explosion happens. This device that
exploded had none of those
characteristics, which means that it was
not a ready device. It exploded um
inadvertently.
That's what I understand thus far of
what's happened. [clears throat] H. So
um this happened and obviously this is
part of a big big uh you know ring of
terrorists all doctors apparently some
of them connect connected to some
terrorists in Kashmir apparently and
whatnot. I think the whole thing is
still under under investigation. So the
blast happened in Delhi and it happened
because the the government agencies
intelligence a agencies were were were
zeroing in on all the terrorists. That's
why it happened. So I think it's not an
int intelligence failure. It's u
actually it was a successful operation
that was going on but obviously
you know
it's it's not that difficult to to set
off an explosive device in some part of
India. It's not that difficult at all.
Any idiot with a with an at IQ can do
it. So that's the problem. That's the
problem this this country faces. Now
after a few hours after the blast there
was a blast in Islamabad. Is this
engineered by Pakistan to to claim
victimhood? Possibly. Possibly. It's
very possible that the Pakistani set off
a blast somewhere in Islamabad just to
make it look like they are also victims
of terrorism and you know that sort of
thing and they are okay with a few of
their people dying. They don't care
zombies, right? So India doesn't
retaliate. Is this the new normal? It
potentially is the new normal, right? So
India has this new doctrine or policy or
whatever you want to call it that um any
act of terror is an act of war. But then
the question is what's the threshold for
war? If three people die in an act of
terrorism in India, is that the
threshold for war? Or if seven people
die, is that the threshold? Is if 20
people die, is that is that the
threshold? What is the threshold? And
that is the problem for the government
of India. You can make a statement that
this is the new normal and this is our
new policy, an act of terrorism, an act
of war. But then
then the question is it's it's easier
said than done, right? You don't want to
start a war
uh when it is not in your let's say
potentially not a good time to go to
war. Let's say hypothetically now is not
a good time to go to war and the
Pakistanis want to pro us into going
going to war. Then should we take the
bait and and go and allow the Pakistanis
to dictate what happens? That's the
problem.
So I think the government will need to
be very clear about what exactly is the
threshold for going to war. Terrorism.
Sure. But what kind of terrorism? What
magnitude of terrorism? If there's a
terror attack in X in which X number of
people die, what is the X which will be
the threshold that has to be crossed for
us to go to war that the government will
have to decide? And obviously it will
come under pressure if this sort of
thing continues to happen. 6P70
Delta says countries like Iran, uh,
Japan and South Korea operate more
submarines than India while only the US
and China have more aircraft carriers
than India. Are we throwing money on the
wrong things?
Look,
there apparently is some kind of new
naval plan in which we're going to be
constructing a lot of warships
apparently. But the point is that the
deadliest warships of the 21st century
are submarines,
right? Aircraft carriers are more for
prestige and more for bullying weaker
nations. I like I've explained in a in a
recent episode, I've gone into detail
into why aircraft carriers are not the
dominant, you know, naval ship anymore.
Submarines are the deadliest naval
ships. Aircraft carriers are good for
projecting power, bullying weak nations,
controlling trade droughts and all, but
they cannot operate successfully in
contested environments. They'll be taken
out. It will be disaster for the morale
of your armed forces.
So, it makes sense for a nation like
India to invest in submarines. Now, how
many submarines do we have right now?
Maybe 15, maybe 16, 17. I'm sure it's
less than 20. A nation of India's size,
a nation that likes to trumpet
Vishwaguru with superpower every other
day. We don't even have 20 submarines.
It's a joke, right? I mean, North Korea
has 60, I don't know, 50 60 submarines.
Pakistan is going to get a bunch of
submarines from from the Chinese.
Pakistan may soon have better
a better submarine capability than us
potentially. I mean, probably not. But
why should they be even like 2/3s equal
to us? Why? What are we doing?
And yeah, okay. We have a couple of
aircraft carriers. Good for us. Uh we
should not invest money on more of these
things. Two is enough for now for the
next 20 30 years. We should invest money
on submarines. So I am a big proponent
of having more submarines. I would say
we should have 50 submarines and we
should invest money on on on on
platforms that can deliver a huge punch
for the least amount of money and that
platforms that will give us distributed
lethality as opposed to concentrated
lethality which is the case of aircraft
carriers. So we should invest in
platforms that make it very difficult
for enemies to operate close to our
maritime regions, close to our
coastlines. So one of the great things
we can invest in is missile boats. A
missile boat will cost $20 million, but
you can put three bramos missiles on
that. And if you have a hundred of
those, we can distribute them all around
our coastline, which will make us a
formidable naval power at least
defensively. We start with defense
obviously first, right?
So that's these are the kind of things
we should be doing and obviously we
should have submarines. We should have
more submarines.
So I don't know what the plans are. We
have some plans for submarines. A few
more nuclear submarine in the next 10
years and all numbers quantity has a
quality of its own as Shri Joseph Stalin
once said very famously.
Um
I don't know whatever that's that's the
situation right now.
6P70 Delta says a French ambassador to
Russia during the 1990s claimed that
during that time Americans used to give
him instructions on what to speak on
which occasion to speak up etc. What's
my opinion? Okay, I am not aware of
this. Um, if a French ambassador has
made such a claim, then it is very
likely to be true because the Americans
at least in the 1990s had this uniolar
moment, right? Their great enemy, the
USSR, had crumbled and disintegrated.
What was left behind was a rump state
called Russia.
An extremely diffident
state, zero confidence, destroyed
economy. The Americans were infiltrating
Russia. uh the entire Russian economy
was been being deconstructed and and
demolished by the so-called oligarchs
whose job was to destroy the economy
right and Yelin was this drunk president
whose greatest joy was alcohol vodka yes
and yeah so that in the '90s the
Americans were at the peak of their
power they were the only superpower they
still are actually but at that time it
was complete uniolarity [laughter]
and no one
uh would want to stand up to them at the
time and that's why they would have this
you know the sense of hubris that the s
of sense of overconfidence and maybe
they may have made such
you know um done such things like giving
instructions to the French ambassador
about what to say in Russia and what not
it's possible it's possible but I am not
aware of this but personally
anonymous scientist says will this Delhi
incident carried out by white collar
terrorists be considered an act of war
then no AM incident is it also looks
suspicious. So NAM is this uh police
station explosion right there was an
explosion in a police station which
destroyed a lot of evidence. Very
convenient isn't it? And the Delhi
incident in which you had a car bomb uh
which claimed I don't know 12 13 15 I
don't know what number it is I hope it
stays as low as possible but it killed
certain number of people. So clearly
carried out by doctors white collar
terrorists. Um the question is were they
connected to Pakistan? They were all
Indian citizens right.
So if we go to war with Pakistan when
Indian citizens have done this even if
they may be connected to Pakistan but
the world will tell point fingers at us
and say that you are now unfairly
unjustly targeting Pakistan when your
own citizens are carrying out terrorism.
Right? So that's the conundrum which is
associated with terrorism. That's the
problem. [clears throat]
The Pakistanis can even have terrorists
come in through Nepal or from Bangladesh
or from Kookiland you know the northern
part of Burma that is currently lawless
where the Americans wants to want to
construct cookie land they can have
terror is coming from coming from there.
There are so many ways of attacking this
country
and then if that happens and if it if
there is no direct connection to
Pakistan
we will be in a position where if you
want to attack Pakistan we have to first
justify that by putting out dosiers by
collecting evidence and giving it to the
United Nations and so on. By the time
the Pakistanis are prepared yeah
something is coming. So you lose the
element of surprise. So the point once
again is if there is an act of terrorism
in the country whether it is directly
connected with evidence to Pakistan or
not what is the threshold that we're
going to decide
that constitutes an act of war if two
lives are lost is that is that going to
be considered an act of war or will it
is it going to be five lives or 10 lives
or 20 lives or what's the number there's
going to have to be some kind of
threshold red line below which we don't
go toward Pakistan if the threat that
threshold is crossed, we go to war. That
is something the government will have to
decide. I'm sure it's going to depend on
the number of lives that are sadly lost
or something like that. Um, at this
point in time, I don't see this this act
of terror.
I don't see it being considered an act
of war right now. The tensions are high
right now between India and Pakistan.
And war could break out anytime if there
is another terror attack on India
potentially. And it's also true that the
longer India waits to deal with
Pakistan, the stronger they will get
because they, you know, they're going to
be supplied arms, ammunition, weapons,
whatnot by the United States and their
proxies. That's going to happen. So the
longer we wait, the the stronger they
will get.
Bjusai says Napoleon once predicted that
the Liana
purchase will lead to the US becoming
highly strong and will humble the pride
of England. Looks like Napoleon was
right.
The Louisiana purchase happened in which
year? 1803 was it?
Let's uh fact check that. Just to fact
check, it doesn't really matter which
year it was. It was in the early 19th
century. Uh Louisana
purchase
Which year was this? 1803 was it? 1803.
Which year was it? 1803. Yes. Uh my
memory for once was right with dates.
Okay. So the Louisiana purchase happened
in 1803
in which the United States purchased
this big piece of territory from the
French from Napoleon and that
essentially roughly doubled the size of
the United States. Right? And that's
something I've spoken about in the past.
I'm not sure whether Napoleon predicted
this or not. I'm not sure what he said
or what he did not say. Uh but if he did
say what you are uh what you've written
here then obviously he's what he said
has come out turn turned out to be true.
Um the US obviously has is the most
powerful nation in the world and England
or the United or the United Kingdom it
was relegated to secondass
uh power status in 1956.
after the SU crisis after it was
humiliated in the Suez crisis and that's
a whole different story. I've I've
spoken about that that at length in the
past. So after 1956 the UK was no longer
a first rate world power. It became a
second rate world power and today the UK
is a third rate world power. It's a it's
a vasal of the US. It's not even a
sovereign nation. It doesn't even have
control of its own nuclear deterrent. So
we know how things have gone. And if
Napoleon did say this then he turned out
to be absolutely correct.
Bijuai says, "Do you think India should
join groups like the G7? Also, will the
US ever try to do with us what they did
to their G7 partner Japan by Plaza
Accords?"
Look, groups like the G7,
they are invite only groups.
Look, tomorrow morning if Bangladesh
decides I'll become a member of the G7,
will they be allowed to be a member of
the G7? No. If tomorrow morning let's
say um Poland decides I I want to become
a member of the G7, will they be given
entry in the G7? No, the G7 is this
group of industrialized nations. Even
China is not a member of the G7 as far
as I know. Right. China it's it's all
these white European nations in the
United States in Canada I suppose and
Australia perhaps. Uh let's let's take a
quick look at which are the G7 nations.
Yeah, let's take a look at that. Which
are the G7 nations?
Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan,
the UK and the United States, not even
Australia. So it's these nations and
this group it's it's not open for
anybody who wants to become a member,
right? It's not it doesn't work like
that. And the question is why should
India want to join a group like the G7?
What do we get out of it? Status. We
should stop playing these status games
and concentrate on wealth and power.
Forget about status. India is a very
performative society. We we we chase
status at the expense of wealth and
power. As a nation, India should only
focus on wealth and power. Forget about
status. What's the point of joining a
group like the G7? What's the benefit?
And even if we want to join, will they
allow us to join? They may invite us
every year for the summit because we are
the third fourth largest economy is
going soon to be the third largest third
largest economy. We can't be ignored.
That's why they they are inviting us
because the global economy doesn't
function without us. That's the only
reason. But they don't like us. If you
said knock, let me join the group.
They'll say take a hike. They'll laugh
you out of the room. Right? Why do you
want humiliation?
It's the same thing as you know wanting
to be a permanent member of the UN
Security Council. They're not going to
allow you to do to become a member.
Whoever is is are the members right now.
Right? So the point is forget about
membership. Become so powerful that you
simply can't be ignored.
The the security council seat permanent
seat. It's all about the veto power,
right? Become so powerful that you have
a veto whether you sit on that seat or
not. That is the point. Forget about
these status games. That's my entire
point to to to
my viewers and to to the people of
India.
Okay. Uh do you think the US will do to
us what they did with their G7 partner
Japan by Pazakot? The see Japan is not
their partner. Japan is their slave.
Japan is their colony. Japan is a vasal
state of the US. Japan is under
permanent US military occupation since
1945. People don't understand this.
People don't realize this. Japan is not
a free nation. Japan is not a sovereign
nation. Japan is an occupied country.
Then as an occupied country, you you
have no choice but to do what the master
says, right? They have 50,000 troops on
your soil. They have 130 military bases
on your soil. What will you do? Will you
go against them? What happens if you go
against them? Remember Shinszo Abbe?
But India is not in that position,
right? So they can't do that to India.
They can't force our RBI,
Reserve Bank of India to, you know,
enact or implement policies similar to
what Japan, the Bank of Japan was forced
to do as part of the Plaza codes, right?
That that won't be possible. So they'll
try to do it in in other ways by
imposing tariffs and whatever else
they're doing. So they'll try to slow
down India's economic growth and maybe
you know harm the country, damage the
country in variety of ways through other
means, not the Plaza code kind of thing.
Okay. Minimalist Maverick says, I really
want India to have 700 plus offshore
bases plus trade routes control plus
reserve currency. How do we achieve this
and replace the US as a true superpower
in 50 years?
You do that by becoming the
overwhelmingly most powerful nation in
the world. And what do I mean by
overwhelmingly most powerful nation? Do
I mean economic power? No. I mean the
power to destroy everybody else. That's
the only way you can do everything else.
How does the US control more than 700 or
800 extr territorial bases? How do all
those countries allow the US to do it?
They they allow the US to have bases in
their countries in their in the on their
soil because the US can destroy them if
they don't allow it. That's how powerful
the US is. The US can destroy any
nation. Dismantle, destroy. That's how
powerful the US is. So you don't want
that to happen. You don't want the wrath
to face the wrath of Uncle Sam. So you
do what they say
and that's why they have this. Why is
the US dollar the reserve currency of
the world?
What enforces the status of the US
dollar as the reserve currency? The
military might of the US enforces that.
So if India wants to be a superpower,
Indians love the status right of being
superpower in Vishaguru. If India wants
to be a superpower, we have to become
the most powerful military nation in the
world.
Even if we are not the most powerful
economy, if we have if if we have a
bigger stick than the US, then we are
the most powerful nation. We are a
superpower and then we can have 700 plus
1,000
extr territorial bases across the world.
Maybe we'll have bases on the on the
moon on Mars also. See, in today's
world, we have to not only be the most
powerful nation from a military
perspective, but also from a
technological perspective. You may have
20 million soldiers, but if they have
100,000 robots, your 20 million soldiers
will be raw meat, right?
Technologically, we have to be advanced.
So, what is the road to superpower
status? Technological superiority and
military superiority. And these two go
hand in hand. And for that, you don't
necessarily need economic superiority.
Not necessarily. If you sacrifice all
the larly bha yojas and all that
nonsense and pour all that money into
into technological military development
then you can become a very very scary
nation in five in like 10 20 years right
so that's how you can do it but if you
have this democratic process and all
these uh all these yojas and whatn not
then nothing will ever happen
says even after getting one after one
crackheads like neu to Mur GI Desa etc.
How did India remain to man? How did
India manage to remain fully sovereign?
Well, let me ask you a question, my dear
friends.
Between 2004 and 2014,
that 10-year period, was India fully
sovereign? Truly sovereign.
Ask yourselves this question.
[clears throat]
Was India genuinely truly truly
sovereign? There have been periods of
time where India was not genuinely fully
sovereign. India is truly sovereign
today. So when I construct my my
rankings,
hard power rankings, I take in factors.
I I consider factors like sovereignty
and GDP and u military spending
expenditure and you know power
projection capabilities uh nuclear
number of nuclear warheads and so many
other things right so when I consider
sovereignty whether a nation is fully
sovereign or not what are the factors in
sovereignty there's territorial
sovereignty there is legislative
sovereignty there is economic
sovereignty there's military sovereignty
those are the four factors I consider in
sovereignty but there's a fifth factor I
don't consider because it's it's hard to
quantify Right. And that is
technological sovereignty. Is India
technologically sovereign? It's not. So
there are big issues.
All right. But we are more or less
territorially sovereign, economically
differently sovereign, legislatively
sovereign.
And what else was there? There's one
more. Whatever that is which I just
said. What are the sovereignty factors?
Economic sovereignty. Military
sovereignty. Yeah. Fourth is military.
So those four forms of sovereignty, we
are fully sovereign in that. But
technologically, we are not a sovereign
nation. Remember that. So we have
issues. Let's not be all like you know
everything is hunky and dory and
everything is fantastic. We've had
issues. We have had periods of time in
the periods of history in the past
between 47 and today and between 47 and
2014 that we were not fully sovereign at
times. Okay. So there have been major
issues.
Kunal Krish says are we waiting for the
trade deal with the US or something else
Pakistan
I think we're just going going forward
with whatever our plans are as a nation
if the trade deal happens with the US
good if it doesn't happen fine no
problem right the US is has
unfortunately decided to adopt a
maximalist stance a maximalist position
in the trade talks what do we mean by
that you give us everything or you or
you give us nothing. That sort of thing.
We want everything. You open your entire
economy to to us. That's the only demand
we have. We will not accept anything
less than that. You have to open up your
entire economy. You have to open up your
agricultural sector and whatever goods
we export into your country, you have to
impose zero 0% tariffs. That's called a
maximalist position. And obviously that
doesn't work for us, right?
Uh so that's why the trade talks aren't
haven't uh yielded a trade agreement
thus far. Uh so are we waiting for it?
No, we are going ahead with whatever we
are doing. If it happens, great. If if
it doesn't happen, fine. We'll deal with
it. Pakistan, I don't know
Pakistan. The sooner we deal with
Pakistan, the better it will be. And
what do what do what do I mean by deal
with Pakistan? Do we again go and do
another operation Synindur and you know
hit another 10 military B air bases and
kill another 300 terrorists and we done
happy. We we slapped them again. We
punched them. What's the point?
What's the objective of a war with
Pakistan? We want an end to terrorism.
We want an end to the nuclear blackmail
which means complete regime change and
and bulcanization of Pakistan. If we
can't achieve that, there's no point
going to war.
So yeah, that's what needs to happen.
How long will we have this this
blackmail
at our western border? How long would we
keep tolerating that? And does Pakistan
exist only so that every few months or
years we'll go and give them a few slaps
and we come back and we say, "Yeah, we
won 30 70 whatever." What's the point of
doing that?
A war should have a definite objective.
And the objective when it comes to
Pakistan has to be bulanization and
regime change and the end of nuclear and
and denuclearization
and an end to terrorism. That has to be
the objective of a war with Pakistan.
Nothing less than that will be well
considered victory. I don't want P like
a few hundred square kilometers of land
to come back to India which will come
with its own problems. I would rather
have a proper bulcanization of Pakistan
end to terrorism then we'll deal with P.
satellite has become a new member. Thank
you very much, sir. And welcome. Thank
you.
Mr. Sakenna says, "Please shed some
light on how the US used Nazi designs
and scientists to get a head start in
almost every technological industry and
monopolize innovation."
So, I won't be able to shed all the
light because there's a lot that's still
under wraps. But I can give you the
example of the US space program which
which did not exist until 194 until
after 1945 until after the Nazi
surrender in the second world war. So
when the Nazis surrendered in 1945 to
the Russians and to some extent the US
at that time the United States did not
have a space program. So what the US did
is that it captured a large number of
German rocket engineers
including the the greatest of them all
Wer von
and these engineers were captured taken
prisoner and shipped to the United
States in an operation called operation
paperclipip I think and the Russians
also captured as many of these rocket
engineers and aviation engineers as
possible. and brought them to Russia
and the Americans also got their hands
on some of the German missiles.
So the uh so Nazi Germany was the
pioneer of not only ballistic missiles
but also cruise missiles and also of the
jet engine. So all of this technology
made its way into the US and in Russia.
But the Americans somehow were very
smart and they got the best engineers
and that's how they started the space
their space program. The first ever
photograph of the earth from space was
taken from a captured V2 missile which
was test flown out of the United States.
And then you had the setup of NASA and
Veron Brown eventually became a
naturalized US citizen. He became the
head of NASA and he was the brain behind
the Saturn Saturn 5 rocket which took uh
American astronauts to the moon. Right.
And uh there was this Horton brothers
flying wing aircraft. Let's take a look
at that. Right. Which was a Nazi German
aircraft. Horton
Brothers flying wing. Take a look at
what this looked like.
This is what this German design looked
like.
Okay.
What does it look like?
Yeah, it it it doesn't it look like the
the American stealth stealth aircraft
that came later.
US Stealth. [snorts]
So it looks you can clearly see the the
that the American B2 Spirit is inspired.
It's it's not just inspired. It is based
on this 1942 German design. So that's
just a couple of examples. There's so
many more examples like this and that's
how the Americans got a head start. So
today when they when they complain about
China stealing their technology and
whatn not that technology was taken from
Germany much of that and built upon. So
the Americans acquired the technology,
they acquired the engineers and then
they built upon that and that's how they
iteratively improved upon things and
today we see where they are.
That's how it happened.
Teen talks Dharma says there are many
ways to run a country like socialism,
communism, capitalism. Is there a rule
to pick one? Aren't India a mixture of
all?
Is India a mixture of socialism,
communism and capitalism today?
See capitalism is a way to of of running
your economy.
Socialism once again it's more about
economy and also
so when you talk about how to run a
country
we're talking about the system of
governance. We're also talking about the
economic system that the country will
adopt. Now the the
economic system doesn't n doesn't
necessarily have to be the same as
as the governances for for example let's
take the example of China okay China
today is nominally a communist nation
okay it's a communist dictatorship but
today people kind of have the right to
property you even have millionaires in
China and the economic system is It's
it's capitalistic in nature, right?
States state uh controlled capitalism.
So it's kind of a weird mixture of
socialism and capitalism. It's the
Chinese way of doing things. They have
learned over time what works best for
their country.
So each country has to figure out what
works best for it. Is India mixture of
socialism, communism, capitalism. I
don't think India is a mixture of
socialism, communism and capitalism.
India
from 1947 onwards was a socialist
country. state controlled economy and
very poorly performing public sector and
tremendous whatever else problems. And
today we have moved more towards an open
market system and there still is some
state control. We still have public
sector units. We still have the
government involved in manufacturing
industry and business and whatnot which
ideally should not be but it is. So it's
kind of somewhere between socialism and
capitalism today. more capitalism than
socialism but a lot of government
control through the bureaucracy and
whatnot. So it's not the best system
today. Uh it's it's a pretty difficult
it's pretty hard to do business but way
better than 1991 right? So we've come a
long way. We we are way better today but
still there's a lot to improve for us.
Is there a rule to pick what works best
for your country? The rule is very
simple. What is your long-term objective
for your country?
Let's say you want to be a superpower.
by let's say um what today's 2025 well
let's say 50 2075 so in 50 years we want
to be a superpower economic superpower
and and military superpower and to be a
military superpower you have to be an
economic superpower let's say we assume
that way so if you want to be an the
largest economy in the world
how do you get there you have to break
it down into into pieces into into
smaller action items let's say or
smaller milestones so if you want to be
let's say a 70 let's say a hundred
trillion dollar economy okay by 2075. So
where do you want to be in 2050?
Maybe you want to be a $50 trillion
economy in 2050. Today is 2025. So where
do you want to be in 2035 and so on. So
you break it down to milestones and you
decide which is the best way to go there
depending on the kind of country that
you have and so on. So that's the rule
to pick what is best for you. That's how
we do it.
Samarura says, "With the recent Delhi
terrorist attack and multiple terrorist
arrests, is operation sindu 2.0 likely?
And how should India handle the US US
response this time?" I don't think
Operation Synindu 2.0 is likely right
now. I don't think so. The terrorists
who were attack who were captured were
Indian citizens.
Yeah. There may or may not be links to
Pakistan. Probably there will be. But
you you if you if you go to war with the
country, you have to have clear
justification.
And even if we know that there is
justification, the world has to be
convinced.
That's the way things work today. So I
don't think there's going to be
operation zindu 2.0 because of this
terrorist attack right now immediately.
I I may be completely wrong. It's
possible. But it looks like it's
unlikely right now. And whenever
operation zindur operation sindur 2.0
zero happens, how do you handle the US
response?
See, what you do is you start and
conclude the operation as soon as
possible. You don't wait for 7 weeks for
the war to conclude. If you wait that
long, the Americans will come and
interfere in 3,000 ways. You finish you
the operation, which means you achieve
your military objectives in 72 hours,
3 days, maybe 4 days, maybe 5 days, not
longer than that. Otherwise, the world
will get the time will will have the
opportunity to formulate a response and
try and squeeze you and create problems
for you. It has to be a blitzkrieg
operation. No dillydallying, no rules of
engagement. Just achieve the military
outcomes that we want. That's it.
Achieve it in whichever way you want.
You have to give that kakl to the
military. Do whatever it takes to
achieve the objectives that we have
given you. Get it done as soon as
possible in the in the shortest amount
of time. If we have that sort of
clarity, the Americans won't have the
time to come and try to impede the
progress of the operation.
Godliness says who is backing Pakistan
against Parat. They all knew we will
respond with Sindur 2.0 after the
massive attack they were planning. It
means Pakistan was ready and is ready
for a conflict with India. Yes, there's
this big
is it a huge mystery as to who is
backing Pakistan against Barat? Is it
such a huge mystery?
Let's go back a few decades.
December 25,
1979, what happens? The Soviets decide
to invade Afghanistan.
Who was the Soviet premier at the time?
Was it Androp? Was it somebody else?
Whoever doesn't matter. The Soviets
decide to invade Afghanistan.
The US sees an opportunity to bleed the
USSR.
So it shakes hands with the Pakistanis.
Yahuk says that a few million dollars
but don't work. It's it's peanuts. I
will need lots of money. So the
Americans give Pakistan lots of money
and lots of weapons and military
advisers and and training personnel who
train the Pakistanis into how to use
terrorism tactics to bleed the USSR, the
Soviet occupiers of Afghanistan. And
after a decade the Soviets are beaten
and they leave humiliated from
Afghanistan. And then all that surplus
terrorist capability that Pakistan had
built up, it is then moved into India.
And even in the 1980s when the
Afghanistan conflict was going on, the
Pakistanis were using terrorism in
Punjab. All of that was funded and
financed by the United States.
And then in 1989 or wherever the the
there's a disaster in Kashmir. The
Kashmiri Hindus are evicted from
Kashmir. Many of them are murdered. Mass
murders and whatnot. All of that was
funded in finance by the United States.
So who do you think is backing Pakistan
against BAT? Do I really have to spell
it out?
An says, "What's the ideal geography for
Bat? ignoring more than
religious/political lines. Should Bat
extend to the South China Sea, even to
Iran or further
look, India is super super congested.
The population density is super high. No
question about that. So what do we do?
Where do we find new land?
Right? We have too many people in this
country. 1.4 billion people in 1947
undivided bat. We had 330 million which
included Pakistan and Bangladesh today's
right. The population density was like
less than a quarter of what it is today.
Imagine the competition for resources
and all the all the stress that that it
brings.
So India needs more space. Yeah.
Question. No question. What do we do? Do
we invade Persia? No, we don't do that.
Come on. That's that's bad. We should
not invade Persia. We should not invade
Burma. What do we do?
Where do we find new land? I suppose we
evict the Chinese from Tibet and then we
kind of merge Tibet with us. Tibet is is
is not easy to live in very high
altitudes. Spend a week in Ladak, you'll
understand how it feels, right? Most
most Indians can't handle that. But you
see, if you want more land, more
territory, you can certainly
bring Pakistan Bangladesh back. But that
will come with its own gigantic
problems. If you don't want those two
nations and neither Afghanistan then I
can only say Tibet but that's on the
other side of the Himalayas. So we'll
have to build highways and all that
which will be huge engineering feats to
cross the Himalayas and go into Tibet.
So the
the ideal geography of Bhat is is what
it's the Indian subcontinent which which
is which it has always been. If you want
more land, the only thing I can see is
Tibet or maybe several some parts of
Central Asia which in which our people
had had settled for thousands of years,
right? No, no, nothing else I can think.
I I I would not be in favor of extending
Baratwash to Iran. That would be well
not nice, right?
Spade says,
"How did even after KGB officers in
Indian political systems were able to
acquire nuclear weapons, did the
Russians know about it? They allowed
it." What? Excuse me. How did
how did even after KGB officers in our
Indian political systems were we able to
acquire nuclear weapons? Did the
Russians know about it? Did they allow
it?
I have no idea.
I'm not supposed to know these things. I
am not a member of the Indian
intelligence. I am not a member of the
Indian government. I was not a member of
the government in the past when all of
these things happened. And these things
are secrets. We're not supposed to know
these things. But assuming let's say
that India was to some extent
infiltrated by external intelligence
agencies maybe the KGP maybe the CIA
both let's say hypothetically
it was well known that India has a
civilian
nuclear program right and the the
Americans Canadians whoever they also
cooperated with us and and sold us some
file material and whatnot in the 20th
century
And um it was well known that we had
this three-stage nuclear program and we
wanted to be a major nuclear
uh power producer and everyone knows
that if you have nuclear reactor
capability then it's it's just a matter
of time before you can develop your own
nuclear weapons especially when you have
breeder reactors which which you know
produce
plutonium and so on.
So it was not a big secret that India
was technologically advanced. We had
good scientists, good engineers
and uh so maybe it was known that India
had the capability and India first
tested a nuclear weapon in what 1974
right in Pran. So when we did that were
the Americans and Russians aware of this
maybe they were maybe they weren't. I
can't say but were they in a position to
not allow us to do it? I don't think so.
Even if they knew it, how could they
have prevented us from doing something
in our own territory? Not really. They
could not. And I'm sure the Russians
would have seen this as not a negative
development from their perspective,
right? Because it would then give the
Russians a different kind of
counterbalance to China because India
and Russia have always been on good
terms and China is a nuclear weapons
power. It became it became so in the
1950s,60s
whenever60s. Yeah. And there was a
problem with Russia. So if China is now
counterbalanced by a different nuclear
power which is India, it's not a bad
thing. But the sad thing is that after
our nuclear test in 1974,
we went to sleep for 25 24 years. We
said it was a peaceful nuclear
demonstration. It was a technology
demonstration. We have no desire to have
nuclear weapons. And we went to sleep.
It's only in 1998 that we tested the
second round the that we conducted the
second round of nuclear weapons tests.
And then we actually developed weapons.
Right? So India has always been this
nation with zero ambition. Always a
nation that is you know punches way
below its weight. It's only now that we
are punching at our weight. That's why
the whole world especially the the major
powers are not pleased with us. Yeah.
Pranayumar says what is the ideal
population of Bharat based on area? 300
million.
300 million 30 crores no three crores
what what is 1 cr
30 crores right okay I'll just say I'm
not I get confused when I transpose
between crores and billions and millions
I'll say 300 million is the ideal
population of bat based on area I would
see around the time of independence
dominant status 1947 undivided bhat had
a population of about 330 million
And that undivided bat included what is
currently Afghan sorry not Afghanistan
but Pakistan and Bangladesh.
So all of that was 330 million people.
Today without Pakistan and Bangladesh we
have 1.4 billion which is a disaster. So
ideally it should be about 300 million
but we should not be in a hurry to bring
it down.
This population you know rebalancing
should happen over the next couple of
centuries not the next 50 years. It'll
be a disaster.
We shall roes government and any terror
attack is act of war. the war. No,
there's going to be
thresholds, red lines. Like I said, this
is most likely not going to be be
something that leads to war, unless I'm
completely mistaken. I could be
mistaken, of course. Uh but see, the
terrorists who have been apprehended in
caught. We're all Indian citizens. I'm
sure they have connections with Pakistan
and sympathies with Pakistan and so on.
But how do we justify war to the world
when the terrorists are Indian citizens?
That's the problem with terrorism. You
see, that's why terrorism is such a
powerful tool for Pakistan and whoever
is financing Pakistan. That's the thing.
I don't see this going to war at this
point in time. Maybe I'm wrong and that
that's that's okay.
TMes Pande says with the far right
surging in Germany, is Europe heading
back towards ideological extremism?
Extremism around the world is on the
rise. So is racism. See, there's
something called Newton's third law,
right? For every action, there's an
equal and opposite reaction. So, when
the European dictatorship, which is
headed in Brussels, which is located in
Brussels, which is a dictatorship, okay,
the the so-called EU government,
nobody voted for it. They are not
democratically elected, but they control
what happens. They decide what happens
in Europe. They decide the policies.
they decide what what kind of people are
made to migrate to Europe and so on. So
right now the past few years what's
happening is that the various EU nations
have been forced to to absorb
refugees a certain number of refugees
every year who are typically military
age males with very few women or
children and they are typically from
only certain countries generally
countries that have Islamic populations.
Right? So when this sort of invasion is
being engineered into your country,
there's going to be a push back. There's
going to be a reaction to that, right?
So Europe will obviously become
radicalized as a consequence
when the leaders of Europe are doing
this to the to the people of Europe.
When they are when they are
re-engineering the demographics of
Europe and destroying what Europe
is, then there's going to be
um the resurgence of the far right, the
right, far right, whatever you want to
call it. I don't consider it to be far
right. It's just a natural defense
mechanism.
Today everything that is not left is far
right
that's how the western media portrays
things and we Indians we read that and
we say oh far right extremism what far
right they are fighting for their
survival
I to some to some extent I feel
sympathetic to them we also face the
same problem but we don't have a far
right right we have a 100 million
potentially Bangladeshes in this country
and we are sitting and we are employing
them as maids and puncture walas and and
vegetables sellers and we have no
problem. Indians have a death wish. The
Europeans probably don't have a death
wish. Right? So that that's what's
happening. And obviously when you have
this situation, there's going to be
racism. What do you expect? What do you
expect?
It's Indians who are like sheep. We have
a 100 million Bangladeshes possibly in
India. And Indians are like, "Oh,
everything is fine. Everything is fine.
We will employ them as our housemaids.
We'll employ them. We will we'll buy
vegetables from from them.
We will
I don't know what else. Indians are like
sheep.
Rywick says someone said last time
recently Migallaya is the center of
tourism. I'm very happy about it as far
as east is as the far east is getting
popular but the most famous place is dai
which is at the Bangla border. Analyze
on map and how can it be a problem?
I remember there was a question about
Dawoki in a couple of episodes ago, two,
three episodes ago. Let's see. Uh
Dawoki, it's it's right on the border
with Bangladesh, isn't it? Dialea.
Dialea.
Zoom in. So, it's a river and it's a
very pretty river. Very transparent
looking river apparently.
And uh
yeah, this is the one. And if we zoom
out, we will find that it's on the
border between India and Bangladesh,
right? It's right on the border and you
will have tourists from both countries
converging in this area apparently.
That's what I've seen. And you have this
boating and whatnot, right? So some part
of this comes under Bangladesh and some
part of it comes uh within India
and there is no demarcation of the
border apparently. Oh, we can see street
view over here. Nice. Nice. It's very
pretty. Dawoki tourist point spot.
Dawoki village.
Okay. So that's the kind of situation we
have here. Let's zoom out.
Okay. So what would you like me to
analyze on the border? It's an open
border. Clearly there is no fencing as
far as I can see.
And that is generally the situation
along large parts of the India
Bangladesh border which is a u something
that is extremely concerning
because we know the situation with
Bangladesh. All the Bangladeshes they
want to move into India,
right? They all want to move into India.
They all seek to to live in India
and uh enjoy the benefits of living in
India. But they have no allegiance to
India as a nation, as a as a
civilization, as a culture. Huge
problem. Huge problem. And that's why
the government needs to do something
about this. So I I noted with great uh
satisfaction and pleasure that uh on the
15th of August, the prime minister of
India, Mr. Modi, he announced that
there's going to be a highowered
demographic uh action force or something
which will do something about the
illegal immigration into India. Well, I
hope that u some action is taken on that
soon. Yeah.
Ainavulkarnney says sovereignty
questioned in open
Japanese sovereignty questioned in open
parliament.
Is that so?
Uh I am not aware of what has happened
in the Japanese parliament but let me
explain what the situation is with
Japan. Japan is not a sovereign nation.
This is something I have been saying for
I don't know years now, right?
I've been saying this, explaining this
for years. Japan is not a sovereign
nation. Japan has a parliament. Japan
has a government. Japan has elections.
Japan has prime ministers who come and
go. Japan has laws. Japan has a
constitution. So from outside it looks
like a proper functioning democratic
nation. You have elections. Obviously
it's a free country, right? But look
behind the scenes, behind the curtains,
and you will see that Japan hosts more
than 130 American military bases on its
territory.
130 American bases, military bases,
permanent military bases, more than
50,000 American troops.
The Bank of Japan is controlled by the
Americans. The Japanese government can't
take a single decision on foreign policy
or or military policy without the
express approval of the American
generals who run the country.
So if you look behind the scenes, Japan
is
under permanent US military occupation.
It is not a sovereign nation. Madame
Prime Minister of Japan, she may say
whatever she says. It is her duty to to
say that Japan is a sovereign nation.
But if you look at the definition of
sovereignty, you will see that Japan
does not fulfill any of the criteria
required for a nation to be democratic.
What about the Japanese constitution?
The Japanese constitution was written by
the Americans and the Japanese
government has not been allowed to
change a single word of the constitution
since 1945. Do you call that a sovereign
nation?
6P70 Delta says, "When asked about
Russian hackers 2016 US elections, Putin
said, "How do they know they are
Russians? They could be Tatar's Jews.
Was he being sarcastic? I have
absolutely no idea. I've not seen this.
I am not aware of what of of this
particular statement by uh President
Putin.
So he said that how do you know there
are Russians? There could be Tatars,
Jews." Was he being sarcastic? I have no
idea. So I've not seen this comment so I
won't be able to answer. If I have seen
it, I may be able to shall we Google
that. Uh Putin 2016 election. Let's see.
Let's see. Let's quickly take a look if
I can find it. Put in 2016.
Uh
hackers, tatars,
Jews. Okay, let's see. Maybe Jews. Maybe
by now. Okay. It's something from 2018.
You're talking about
You're talking about something he said
in 2018.
Okay, that that is something he was he
said what seven years ago.
Maybe they're not even the Russians.
Maybe the Ukrainians Tatars Jews just
with Russian citizenship. I don't know.
Was he being sarcastic? Probably if he
is talking to Megan Kelly, if he's
talking to the Americans, he's going to
be very sarcastic at times. So maybe he
was being sarcastic.
Uh okay sonjutasu says your views on the
mitrokin archives are they credible
the mitrokin archives I think there is
some credibility to it yeah
I haven't studied them in detail but I'm
aware of Shitrokin
and some of the things that he said how
subversion is done and so on which which
is something the Americans do better
than the Russians by the way
And I'm sure that he spoke about
something about India being compromised
in certain ways. I'm sure
some or much of it may be true but the
details I don't recall right now so I
can't say but I think there is certainly
significant credibility to the Mitroin
archives.
Godliness says the US is still the only
superpower around the globe. Trump is
dancing like an emperor and still he
used the term G2 when while meeting she.
It seems the G2 word was used to just to
make she happy but nothing in real.
See like I have said so many times over
the hundreds of episodes in which I have
spoken, there is a vast difference
between words and actions.
Indians love words. India is a
performative society. India is a society
of slogans which is why we pay so much
attention and so much importance. We
place so much importance on words.
Oh, he said something fantastic. Let's
celebrate. Who the hell cares about
words?
Actions is what matters.
So Trump met Shei and before he meets
Xi, he says that G2 is about to convene
and after he meets Xi, he says that God
bless the United States and the and
China and so on. Words, words, words.
What have been the actions?
Nothing. It's business as usual, right?
You think she will be happy because
Trump used the word G2, the term G2. She
doesn't care. She is not Indian, right?
She doesn't. The Chinese don't start
dancing when somebody says a couple of
nice things about them. The Chinese
don't care.
The Chinese do Chanakini a million times
better than Indians. And that is a
crying shame for all of us.
We focus on slogans, on words, on
flattery. The Chinese don't care. They
look at your actions.
So you think if you think that Trump
made she happy by using the term G2,
what can I say? It made no difference to
she. No difference whatsoever.
And overall the Chinese kind of came out
on top in that in that summit meeting.
Last last okay last says what do you
think was the main reason for the allies
winning World War II? Cracking of
Enigma, Operation Barbarosa, internal
sabotage or still classified at all?
Well, different factors. The cracking of
the Enigma code. It it it was a
significant breakthrough and it allowed
the allies to start hunting down all of
those uni boots, the U2, the the the
Ubot, right? That was a sign huge
setback for the Germans. That's that's
one element, small element. Um,
operation Barbarosa was a massive
element in Germany's, you know, the
beginning of the decline of Germany
because uh
instead of finishing off Britain, they
decided to go after Stalin. Stupidity.
They should have finished off Britain
first, right? Then the history of the
world would have been different. But
they go decide to go after Stalin and
instead of going for Moscow they go down
south to the caucasses. They decide to
go do that first at the end of the day
because there is oil in the caucases
right. So at the end of the day they
dealed here there everywhere and they
were punished by first of all by the
greatest Russian general which is
General Winter and then the
and then the Russians just steamrolled
the Germans over time. internal sabotage
not really still classified I'm not sure
can't say how do I how do how do I know
so I would say mainly it is Barbarosa
that stupid mistake of going for Russia
before finishing off the UK
an says how does the US's $ 38 trillion
debt play a part in it geopolitical
position I see all this debt and insane
money printing cause incredible
corrosion internally and fall in
external position
Look, this debt, the Americans are not
worried about the debt. The debt isn't
is in US dollars, right? So, all they
have to do is to print more dollars.
Obviously, it'll cause inflation. It
will destabilize the economy, but they
can do that if if required. And the debt
machinery is so opaque and so so
convoluted
that it it is very hard to to wrap your
heads around it. And it's very hard to
explain how the machinery of debt works.
Nations buy debt.
Nations do not ever want to repay debt
today. Look at the debt to GDP ratio of
Japan. Look at the debt to GDP ratio of
various EU nations.
None of them is ever going to pay off
the debt. To whom do they owe the debt?
To whom does the US owe this debt? First
of all, do they owe the debt to China,
to India, to Japan, to the EU, to
somebody else?
To some extent, they do owe some debt to
these countries. But a lot of the debt
they owe to themselves.
How does that work? Yeah, it's super
complicated. I can't explain to you in 5
minutes. So much of this debt is owed to
itself.
It's all handwaving and you know,
creating dollars out of nothing, that
sort of thing.
So X bank will owe to Y bank and that
sort of thing that the the super
complicated and the whole system is
designed in such a way that it is meant
not to be understood by anyone except
for the people who run the thing.
So if if the US wants to get rid of the
debt, what will they do? Maybe they will
dump it all into cryptocurrency and then
deflate the cryptocurrency just blow it
out of existence or something like that.
So the Americans have created the system
and they know how to use the system and
it's not like somebody anyone's going to
be able be in a position to force them
to pay money. Right.
James Jamal. Oh, James is now Jamal.
James Jamal. Even Bengali agree Kolkata
was better under the British. Well, you
see James Jamal. The problem with
Kolkata today is that there are more
Bangladeshies apparently than Indians in
Kolkata. And during the British Raj,
we did not have Bangladesh or
Bangladeshies in Kolkata.
So I would agree with those who may
claim that Kolkata was better under the
British because you did not have
allegedly several scores of Bangladeshes
squatting on the streets of Kolkata.
Yeah.
UMX says why are Indians so obsessed
with western names? Look at building
names in Mumbai. Ludha Bellissimo. What
the hell is this building in India? Is
it in India or Italy? Have you seen the
names of schools
in India or colleges? St. Xavier's,
St. Paul,
St. Anthony,
St.
Frederico, Saint Barbarosa,
Saint God knows what else. Put a saint
somewhere and then the school becomes
substantially better. Apparently
when it comes to names of buildings,
when it comes to names of projects, when
it comes to names of cars,
when it comes to whatever names of
people,
names of children,
you know Indians are obsessed with
western everything western. Indians have
this gigantic inferiority complex.
Indians have this gigantic
self-loathing.
They they are ashamed of their culture.
They are super drainated. They think
that if you want to be cool, you have to
sound western.
And what is the reason for this? What
has caused this? It's the education
system. It is your teachers and
professors. It's your media. It's your
entertainment industry. It's your
so-called leaders, all these people.
It's the fact that you are made to study
in English. If you want to have any
chance of getting a good job, it's the
fact that if you want to get a good job,
you have to answer the interview
questions in English. If you speak in
your native language, out you go. India
is completely colonized. So why are we
surprised that this is the situation
today? In 50 years, India may not even
be a Hindu nation anymore. Of course,
today India is not a Hindu nation. We
are a secular nation. Good for us all.
Good for us all. We are digging our own
graves.
UMX says Iranians now think that their
empire reached India. It did, didn't it?
There was this this creep called Nadsha
who did invade India, who did conquer
parts of India and who supervised a
one-day massacre of the people of Delhi.
He stood at tops a mosque which still
exists apparently in Delhi and from
there he gave the order for a general
massacre of the Indians the the citizens
of Delhi men women children Nadsha but
the point is Nadasha was not Persian
he was a Turk Nadsha was not Persian he
was a Turk who ruled Persia
just he he was the same for the Persians
as Orurange was to us but different
because The Persians were Muslims. So
Nadesha did not oppress the Persians.
But Orurb oppressed us because we were
Hindus.
But ethnically Nadasha was not Persian.
He was a Turk.
But today Iran Iranians are like, "Yes,
we we we conquered India." That sort of
thing. Some some Persians are like that.
Not all. Not all.
Persia lost its sovereignty
about 1,400 or so years ago. It's never
regained its sovereignty. Right.
So if if Nadesha conquered India, it was
not Persia that conquered India. It was
the Turks who conquered some part of
India. Yeah. Briefly,
right?
Aravshaw says
brainwashed student says what would Mr.
Gandhi do in this geopolitical
situation? AC says what would Mali do?
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, you seem to have been paying
attention to me. I think that's
something I would have said on Twitter
or something, right?
So people say, you know, there are
certain politicians who will say on
Twitter that we have various options in
geopolitics. We we can follow what Mr.
Gandhi would do or we can follow who
some other person would do and so on,
right? Or what Gotham Buddha would do.
My point is what would
goddess Kali do?
Why do we only have to look at these
these these these people who prioritize
nonviolence and passivity?
And if you want to talk about what would
Gotham Buddha do, I'm sure the samurai
asked themselves what would Gotham
Buddha do because the samurai were
apparently Buddhists, right? Even though
they had a lot of Hinduism also in them.
The samurai were Buddhist warriors who
were vegetarians. They apart from eating
fish. They did not eat any other meat.
Were the samurai
passive believers in nonviolence? No.
They were some of the deadliest warriors
ever. So the point is we have to look at
things in a in a in the proper
perspective. Don't ask yourself what Mr.
Gandhi would do. Ask yourself what your
gods and goddesses would do. Each Indian
god and goddess carries a weapon. Each
god each goddess carries a weapon. Why
do they carry weapons?
Why are they for display?
So yeah, it's it would be relevant to
ask yourself what would
Ma Ali do? What would she do? Yeah. And
what answer would Mr. Gandhi have to
that? Would Mr. Gandhi said that Ma Ali
is wrong. Would he dare say that? Ask
ourselves that too. Right. Right.
Godliness says from last one year reform
is willing winning all the elections in
the UK. The right is banging on the
streets and people are desperate for a
change even ready for a conflict if
necessary. Kia Star Tarmer is struggling
badly. Here Star Tmer is a loser. The
guy has zero leadership qualities. He
has been appointed.
He has been placed in that seat. The US,
the UK parliament, the whole system is a
rigged game. Now the UK is the western
version of Japan. In Japan, every few
months there's a new prime minister.
It's a revolving door kind of situation,
right? Every few months, there's a new
prime minister. A few months later, the
prime minister is gone. A couple of
years down the line, you don't even
remember who was the prime minister 2
years ago. That's the situation in
Japan.
That's the situation in the UK also. So
before Kir Starmer, who was there as the
prime minister? Was it uh Rishi Sunnak
before Rishi Rishi Sunak there was some
lady right what was her name I forget
her name then you had Boris Boris
Johnson you had David Cameron at some
point in time you had some guy called
Brown
I don't know how many prime ministers
have come and gone in the UK what's the
process by which they come and go that
also I'm not clear anymore I don't I
don't care anymore it doesn't matter
anymore the UK is not important it's not
relevant in global affairs it's a third
rate world power It's a vasal. It's a
colony of the US. And yeah, I mean, what
are is the government of the UK doing
about what's happening in the country?
What is happening to the women folk and
the girls
of the country? What have the Pakistanis
been doing to them for decades? And
people like Kir Star Tour have been
covering it all up. Shameless people.
Then they come and lecture us about
human rights and democracy. First, take
care of your women, take care of your
daughters, shameless people, a bunch of
cowards and losers.
And the same applies to the people of
the UK as well. Why are you tolerating
these these so-called leaders who are
covering up what's happening to your
people, to your girls? Why don't you
oust them, dethrone them through
whatever means necessary? If you don't
do that, you are cowards.
Cowards.
UMX says the Brits are very divi very
obsessed with dividing and conquering.
They even talk about this technique
while teaching computer science courses
in prestigious universities. The Brits
are a nation of it's a there have been
their time is gone. It'll never come
back. In a few years the UK is going to
be the Islamic Republic of the United
Kingdom. It's going to be Londonistan,
Londonistan. And it will serve them
right. They are going to pay for the
sins that they have that they have
perpetrated on on the entire world that
they have committed
through you know through their various
actions in the world especially in the
Indian subcontinent. They're going to
pay for it. It is karmic justice. So
they can talk about dividing and
conquering and all that nonsense.
They themselves are being divided and
conquered right now. Serve them right.
Rahul says, "Why secret societies make
their members commit a taboo?
How do members of the societies benefit
by being a member? Could the Epstein
case be such a taboo?" Look, I am not a
member of any secret society. So, I can
only speak about this in hypothetical
terms. But uh look if you are a secret
society okay and you want it you want
the society to remain a secret you don't
want the world to know about it then you
have to ensure that none of the members
of the society
dares to reveal the existence of the
society to the world or reveal any of
the secrets. So how do you ensure it?
You can take an oath,
you know, you can make every every
member sign a document and and give a
promise and all that. But these are just
words, empty words, right? It's like you
you have to put your faith in the person
and everything depends on the person
keeping the trust. People are known to
gossip. So how do you ensure that this
their lips remain sealed? You ensure
their lips remain sealed by having
something called leverage on those
people. So you have them commit
something that is not to be done,
something very nasty and then you ensure
that evidence of that is recorded that
way. Everybody has done it. Everybody
has some le has that leverage on
everybody else. So everybody is then
bound by that common thing that common
taboo or whatever you want to call it.
Right?
So that's how it's done. Now how do
members of such societies benefit by
being a member? Somebody the first
question I took today is that is is was
that why don't we all become start a
deep state my point was what will we
benefit by starting a so-called deep
state first of all we will be starting
it in public a deep state is supposed to
be hidden it's supposed to be a secret
society secondly by starting this this
group of people
what will be achieved cha
it has to have some objectives for the
objectives to be to be achieved you need
to have means to achieve the objectives
it means money and power. Without money
and power, it's just going to be a
gossip group, right? So, how do members
of s such societies benefit by being a
member? By being in proximity, and
connection and allegiance with other
very powerful and wealthy people. That
way you can get things done. So, each
member of the societ society depends on
everybody else to get things done. And
by cooperating, you can get way more
done
in a mutually beneficial way than by
being isolated and not being in
connection and with everybody else.
That's that's how you know that's how
you benefit by being a member of such an
alleged hypothetical secret society.
Could the Epste be such a taboo? It
could be such a taboo. Potentially,
hypothetically, it could. Absar is a new
member. Thank you very much, sir. Thank
you. Very nice of you. And let us all
welcome Abirub to the channel. Thank you
very much.
6P70 Delta says, "Your opinion on the
recent Ukraine corruption scandal?" I
have no idea. Ukraine is
it's corrupt. Is there a scandal? Is is
that the big surprise? I am not aware of
whatever new new thing has happened. But
it's super corrupt. I mean, Zalinsky is
a corrupt person. Zelinski, his entire
role is to ruin his country for the
benefit of the US and NATO. Isn't that
corruption?
How how does the Ukraine benefit
Ukraine? Ukraine is being ruined. That
is the biggest example of corruption you
can have.
So
if there's a corruption scandal, there's
no surprise.
Rywick says, "You were absolutely
correct saying Indians are naive. People
are focused on doctors doing attack but
it has nothing to do with profession
it's religion.
All right. So my policy is that I don't
discuss religious matters and I don't
discuss Indian politics. So I'm going to
say okay sir.
Right. All right. And and thank you.
AKS Baga says your opinion on Shik
Hassina said there were no foreign coup.
Um I am not sure what she has said. I I
I heard that she recently gave an
interview to some of to some Indian
media organization. I don't know which
one but I haven't read it. I haven't
seen it or read it. I have not seen the
video if it exists and I've not read the
transcript of the interview if that has
been put out. I'm sure something has
been put out. I am not aware. But it's
okay. I don't need to know her opinion.
Doesn't matter.
I don't care what she says. She doesn't
say
what happened was a coup. It was
orchestrated by the US and I had
predicted that coup 9 months before it
happened. The video is on the channel. I
made that video 9 months before the coup
happened. So it's okay whatever she says
or doesn't say. But
it was a US uh induced coup. No question
about that. Dhir says each and every
Hindu life is invaluable. They can do 10
attacks in which only five people die
with a collective death toll of 50 and
we shouldn't go to war. Spinelessness is
emboldening them.
Each and every life Hindu life. Yeah.
Okay. Is invaluable. No question about
that.
But do you understand how people rule
countries?
How do people rule countries? Do they
look at each individual tragedy? Does
the prime minister of India look at each
individual tragedy or does he see India
as a nation of 1.4 billion people and
[snorts] then draw red lines based on
numbers?
I am not advocating we do it this way or
that way. I am only prognosticating how
things are done. You see when you are
running a country of 1.4 people, 1.4
billion people, you cannot
deal with these situations emotionally.
I think it was the infamous Mr. Stalin
who said that one death is a tragedy, a
million deaths is a statistic.
I know it was Talin who was a very nasty
person who said that but that's kind of
the approach that rulers and leaders
have
uh in ruling a country.
So I would say that you know we should
go to war even if one person dies. I
would agree with you but if I was I will
agree with you sitting here but if I was
in that position maybe I would see
things differently. We have to be a
little mature and a little less
emotional sir about these things. Each
death is a tragedy. And each death is
intolerable. I agree. But when you're
ruling a country, you have to put your
emotions aside. And sometimes you have
to tolerate. You have to have tolerance.
See when people go to war, when the
Americans did operation desert storm.
Yeah. How many soldiers did they lose?
Several thousand. Did they start crying
and weeping about that? How many
aircraft did the US lose in operation
desert storm? More than 50.
Allegedly, apparently,
it's possible we may have potentially
perhaps lost a few aircraft.
Allegedly in operation sindur and
Indians start crying, oh my god, we lost
x number of aircraft. Who the hell
cares? You need to have some tolerance
for these things otherwise you will
never succeed as a country. That is my
point.
But I agree with you that even a single
death is intolerable. Each life is
valuable.
But when you're ruling a country, it
will be a different length through which
you see these things. That's all I'm
saying. I don't disagree with you in
what you say. Sum Kumar says, "Your
analysis on China Japan recent feud in
Taiwan."
So the the the Japanese Prime Minister
Miss I forget her name. Taki Sai
Taki. She recently said that you know if
the Chinese make a move in Taiwan it
could invite a military response from
Japan or something like that. She said
something similar to along those lines.
She said and the Chinese have gone
ballistic about that and they have you
know dragged out all the old history of
Japan and said said that Japan has been
a very bad nation during second world
war and they did all kinds of atrocities
and Japan should uh stay away from this
wrong behavior and learn how to behave
and um China will not tolerate this and
we will take care of our national
security and that sort of thing. So it's
a war of words. Now why has the Japanese
prime minister said this? because Japan
is a US wasal and they will say whatever
the US tells them to say.
Now in 2023
Henry Kissinger had said that within 5
years Japan will be a nuclear power
nuclear weapons power. So we are in 25
that's 2 years ago right? So 3 years to
go. So the way things are going based on
the statements coming out of Japan at
the US at the at the behest of the US it
looks like Japan could become a nuclear
weapons power in the next three or so
years. So maybe Kissinger will turn out
to be right. Um yeah, so as China's
clout and power, hard power grows, the
Americans will take specific actions to
contain China and Japan is a very
important component of that policy.
So we are seeing steps in that
direction. Right.
Vun says word
Harken Cross.
Uh, it's not Harken Cross. I'll tell you
what it is. Okay, give me a second. Uh,
it is Haken Croitz. H A K E N K R E U T
Z. Haken Croits. How shall I? Here we
have it. Haken Croits. That is the word
that we are talking about. Haken Croits.
Uh, now where was that?
Right. So the word is hacken cro it
means hooked cross
arian stolen from narrative building.
Okay, that's a historical question.
That's not quite a geopolitical
question. But yes, uh as I have u spoken
about multiple times u the German word
for the the symbol is haken croitz. It's
not the swastika and the swastika is an
Arian symbol which means it is an Indian
symbol and it's also something that's
been used across the world even in
Africa and whatever else in the Americas
and it's always been a symbol of
apiciousness
and the Nazis they stole it from us and
today the the the the Europeans and the
west insist on using the term swastika
so that we can't use it as a symbol of
of as a Hindu symbol right so it's
clearly
you know, nasty behavior. [laughter]
So, it's it's our civilizational symbol
that the Nazis stole and misappropriated
and used for very nasty purposes.
Rhythmic says the US has so many vasals.
Tell the vasals of China and Russia.
Kazakhstan, Belarus, Iran are the vasals
of Russia. Please enlighten me. Okay.
The US has lots of vasals. We don't need
to list those. How many vasals does
Russia have? Russia. One is Belarus.
Sure. Right. Belarus the the Russians
have even placed nuclear warheads on
Belarus territory. So Bellarus is a
Russian vasal. Sure thing. Um
what other vas do they have?
I would say various central Asian
nations to some extent or the other
other are kind of
potentially semiaalss of of Russia. Of
course, some of these nations have also
been dallying with American vasalhood.
So if you want to make it clearcut, I
would say Belarus definitely is
uh Kazakhstan,
Usbakistan to some extent are I mean
they still cannot do things that the
Russians will not agree to. So so
Kazakhstan,
Tajakistan, Usbekistan,
Turkmanistan etc. they are definitely
within the Russian sphere of influence
and they will find it very hard to do
things that cross Russian red lines. So
to that extent if you want to call that
vasalhood you could Russia the Russians
don't have
permanent troops in any of these
countries as far as I know I could be
mistaken if the Russians have permanent
military installations and troops then
you have vasalhood right away Iran
well Iran is not a Russian vasal India
Iran is a you could say a Russian ally
ally
u is Iran completely sovereign well it
is very very dependent on Russia and
China for its economic survival. So you
I would say it is not economically
sovereign and because of all the
sanctions the Americans have imposed on
it, it is also not completely sovereign
in various other ways. So Iran is not a
vasal of Russia or China but it is very
strongly dependent on them which gives
them a tremendous amount of leverage
which kind of means. So Iran is in a
gray zone that way. Um, so you could say
if you want clear-cut vasal, it is
Barus.
Do we have anybody else in the Russian
periphery? Mongolia? No. Um, I'm um
yeah, I would say only Barus 100% sure.
China. What about China? North Korea.
Nobody else.
China only has North Korea. Um, once
again, Iran is not exactly a vasal. It
is dependent on China very very
strongly. So kind of gray area but only
North Korea is a proper vasal of China.
Does India have a vasal? India doesn't
have a vasal.
Yeah, unless
we don't talk about it. ICMBBS says,
"What's your personal Indian
geopolitical pet peeve?" My personal
Indian geopolitical pet peeve is that
the Pakistanis are better at following
Chanekiti than India.
That's my personal Indian geopolitical
pet peeve. The Pakistanis are better at
following Chanakiti than India.
Ritik P says, why does Turkey block if
helicopter delivery? I'm not sure what's
happened. Some people are alleging that
the that the Turks have blocked it. Some
Apache helicopters being delivered to
India. The Turks have blocked it. Well,
my question is if the Americans want to
deliver those helicopters to India, will
the Turks dare to block that?
Will the Turks dare to come in the way
of the United States delivering
something to some place?
No. So maybe the Americans want to put
the blame on the shoulders of Turkey and
delay a delivery of helicopters to
India. Okay, let's look at things in a
broader perspective. Let's not look at
let's not let's not do a simple surface
level analysis. We can go a couple of
layers deeper because we have to
understand Turkey is an American vasal.
It's a member of NATO. The Americans
have placed nuclear weapons on Turkish
territory. The Americans have troops on
Turkish territory. Turkey is a US vasal.
Will a US vasal dare to disobey the
master? There will be severe
consequences, right?
Have you seen the the Americans getting
angry with Turkey? Nothing. So, who's
really playing the mischief? Tell me
now.
6P70 Dela says what's your opinion on
ladla engine yoja I have absolutely no
idea what that is sir I'm very sorry
what is a ladla engine yojna I don't is
it something to do with Indian politics
I have no idea
says are we really territorially
sovereign we only show Gilgit Baltistan
and Akai on map but we have no control
over them Indian travelers like me
cannot even visit our own our own scardu
valley and Gilgit
What we show on the map is what we claim
to be our territory.
Gilgit Baltistan
is currently under Pakistani occupation
and from
a facts on the ground reality
perspective it is currently not our
territory. Even though legally and
morally it is our territory we are not
in a position to hold it right now. So
we don't have ter sovereignty over that
part.
of the subcontinent neither over Axai
right so what we show on the map is
where we desire our sovereignty to be
but that's not the case right
but wherever we have boots on the ground
we have complete sovereignty
so China shows Arunachal Pradesh in
their territory on the map right from
using using the same argument as you
China shows Arunachal Pradesh in their
maps
as part of China but they don't have
control over Arunachal Pradesh. So does
China really have territorial
sovereignty? Please explain.
It works both ways. Right? So the point
is the maps show what you desire
to be your sovereign territory. It
doesn't show the actual realities,
ground realities. But whatever the
ground realities are, we have complete
sovereignty there. That is the deal. So
I would also want to I want to go by
road to to Tashkan and Samarand via
Gandhar. I want to do that. I'm not in a
position to do that. I would like to
drive. I would like to drive all the way
to Tashkan and Samarand via Gandhar
stopping in Kabul.
I'd like to spend three four days in
Kabul.
Yeah, I would like to do that but I
can't. So we all face that situation. So
India needs to become more powerful and
regain access to the territories that
should be ours and regain access to the
parts of the world that we have always
had access to via friendly nations such
as Gandhar like Afghanistan. Right.
Prattana says Jewish influencer started
racism against Indians over H1B but
whites whites have turned against them
as well as Israel. Can it impact Israel
US relations? A Jewish influencer
started racism against Indians over H1B
and whites have turned against them as
well as Israel. Okay. I am not aware of
any of this situation. Which Jewish
influencer started racism against
Indians? I I am not aware of this at
all. So since I'm not aware of it, I
can't really comment.
But let's say hypothetically there is a
situation like this that I am not aware
of. So some Jewish influencer apparently
has started racism against Indians on
H1B and whites have turned against them
against whom? Against us or against the
Jew Jewish influencer
against Israel?
[clears throat]
Yeah, I'm not really sure what the
situation is. Whites have turned against
them.
Which them? You are mentioning once one
Jewish influencer, right? It is not
Jewish influencers,
not plural, it is singular. So who has
the who have the whites turned against?
Okay, it's not very clear what you're
saying. I'm I'm really sorry but I'm not
able to exactly get what you're saying.
Ritik P says, what leverage has India
lost after exiting Tajakistan bear base?
Ah,
did we even operate that base? The which
one was it? Was it a Was it farore?
So we apparently in the 2000s had these
two air bases right in and faror and
that now news has come out that
apparently they have exited from one of
these Tajakistan
or Farour. Uh so look if you have an air
base there then you can attack Pakistan
from the northern side from the
Tajakistan area. So you can attack
Pakistan at the same time simult
simultaneously from two sides. It gives
you an advantage over Pakistan.
But if you exit Tajakistan,
so it kind of you know you you lose that
advantage in case you had it. I'm not
sure if we even had that air base in an
fully operational manner. Did we have
Suko over there? If we had Sukco there,
how did we take the Suko there? Because
you can't overfly Pakistan with Suko.
They will they'll be frightened, right?
they won't allow it.
So if we had suko, how would how did we
get them there? Did we fly the suko over
Iran
and into central Asia or I'm not sure
what the situation was. So I don't think
it's a big deal especially with the
Afghanistan situation. Afghanistan and
India are allies, right? That Taliban
and India and Taliban and Pakistan have
a huge territorial dispute.
So let's see how things develop over
there. There is another air base, a
bigger one in Afghanistan.
Ankit G says about GPS spoofing.
Question about GPS spoofing. YouTube is
dismissing my question. Well, I'm sorry
to hear that. YouTube. YouTube. What can
I say about YouTube? YouTube is my best
friend, isn't it? What? Uh 949,000. That
is the number. That is the number now
for me. 949,000. There is somebody in
YouTube who is not a fan of me.
Okay. There is some person, some
individual, some fantastic gentleman or
lady who works in YouTube who is not a
big fan of me. I'm not sure if that
person is in YouTube USA or YouTube
India,
but that person has hardcoded something
into the YouTube parameters saying that
my channel will never cross 949,000.
Okay, it's okay. [laughter]
And apparently it is doing some nasty
stuff with Ankita G also and and
dismissing her question. Anyhow, so
let's [laughter]
um GPS spoofing.
So recently we've had this news right
that's come out on social media that
there is there's been some um GPS
spoofing issues
over the airspace in Delhi also
potentially Mumbai. So when you do GPS
spoofing it means that when you are an
aircraft who wants to land in let's say
an airport
it means that you will not get precise
GPS information in your aircraft. See as
a pilot you depend on GPS coordinates
right? You depend on GPS the satellites
to know exactly what your location is
what your air speed is what your
altitude is and so much more. you have
probably not altitude because you have
altimeters and all that but a lot of
parameters come from the GPS satellites
and you also want to know exactly where
the runway is and maybe you want to use
you know the autopilot using GPS to land
automatically perhaps potentially so you
need GPS if you are a commercial airline
pilot and if there is a problem getting
the GPS signal or if you're getting
wrong signals then it's a very dangerous
situation
So that essentially is is kind of what
GPS spoofing is
and u I'm not sure what is the origin of
these issues. Is Pakistan playing some
games and uh jamming GPS signals over
the airspace of certain major airports
in India? Or is the Indian government
potentially doing that to prevent a
terror attack or a Pakistani missile
attack over these airports? Or is the US
government, you know, messing up the GPS
signals to Indian airports? I'm not sure
what the situation is, but it's
concerning.
And what is the solution to this? The
solution to this is for India to develop
a spinal column
and to have our own proper
alternative to the GPS satellites. We
have something called Navic.
Is the Navic system still operational?
I'm not sure. Let me check take a look
at that. Navic, right? N A V IC. We had
some seven satellites. Very very
um low ambition thing. I NSS with Navic.
How many satellites do we even have?
It covers India and a reg region
extending 1500 km. Look, the Chinese
alternative to GPS is global. The
Russian alternative GLONAS to GPS is
global. GPS is global. But Indian Navik
IRNSS is just subcontinent based. Why is
India
why does India lack ambition?
So how many satellites do we have? Uh
some system consists of a constellation
of eight satellites. Two additional
satellites on ground as standby.
Uh
what's the situation right now? What is
the system clock failure happened?
Indian atomic clock.
Israel space agency. Navic chief time
frame
is it operational right now? Is it
properly operational?
If it is properly operational, why are
we not using it? Why are airports using
it? I'm not sure what the deal is.
Okay, I will not do the research right
now, but clearly we need to develop a
spine and if GPS doesn't work, we should
be able to seamlessly switch to our own
uh GPS alternative.
Right? That's what needs to happen. For
that, you have to put the capabilities
in place. We have to launch lots of
satellites and make it a global system
and have redundancy built into the
system which means if one satellite two
satellites go down the system still
works or we can rapidly launch more
satellites.
Do we have those capabilities? Do we
have the ambition? Do we even
figure in the space race at this point
in time? I don't know what what's what's
going on in India really. So that is
there are some aspects that are pretty
disappointing as as of now.
Prattana says not sindur too but we need
chhatogram chicken neck. I would not
disagree with you.
Yeah. So if you look at the map
you know
look any nation that is self-respecting
will shape its neighborhood to its
advantage. If the borders aren't good
then it will change the borders.
So we have chhattogram. Chhatto
chhattogram is this place right? So
there is a chicken neck here which
between you know which is about uh
30 35 km wide which connects the chogram
area to the rest of Bangladesh. So that
is kind of Bangladesh's chicken neck and
obviously India can anytime take that
region and take chogram back into India.
Chhattogram should never actually have
been part of Bangladesh in the first
place.
So uh that is something we can do
whenever it is required. We can also
take Rangapur etc and and widen the
chicken neck over here significantly if
and when required in the future. So that
is something that is not a big deal. It
it's not like we will face a lot of
resistance from Bangladesh. The Indian
army has tremendous military superiority
and uh that can be done if required in
the future.
Minimalist Maverick says 2024 was a
whole year of aliens and UFO spottings
and the 2020 year was a year of viruses.
Why is everything stone cold
as though it didn't even happen the
first time?
What is stone cold right now?
Yeah, 2020 was the year of the virus and
it looked like the whole of the 2020s
will be the decade of the virus and
thankfully it's not the case thus far.
So COVID is now a bad bad dream kind of
it's a it's a bad memory but we have
moved on from COVID and nobody will
tolerate any more lockdowns. People are
sick and tired of lockdowns and 2024 was
a year of aliens and UFO spottings. Yes,
the whole of the US was inundated with
UFO sightings and so so much more. And
apparently these were all US government
drones
because after Trump came to power his uh
his press secretary she said that these
were US government drones that were
spotted over New Jersey and whatnot. So
those drones were were
filmed by various people
transforming from drones into orbs. So
that is pretty advanced technology
clearly. So that was a deal in 2024. Now
we don't see we don't see these reports
of UFOs over over American skies that
much anymore. So why is everything stone
cold now?
I can't speculate. I don't know. I hope
it stays stone cold. I don't want new
aliens to come to the to our planet or
or I don't want any aliens to come to
the planet. We would like to have a
peaceful existence isolated from the
rest of the universe, isolated from all
the other alien species that may or may
not exist out there. And we don't want
any new virus outbreaks. Good gods, we
don't want that. That COVID thing was
enough. Yeah. So, I hope it stays that
way.
Right. Uh, Bronny Batman says, "Where
did this Kailash Satyarti vanish? Never
saw him rescue children or do any
service. He got a Nobel Prize. What did
the deep state plan with him?"
Well,
I am sure he is there are plans for him.
I'm sure. See, Muhammad Yunus, that
fellow he won the Nobel Prize
several years ago and he kind of
vanished too, right? Until he has
resurfaced now and he is the chief
adviser of whatever the hell he is for
the military dictatorship of Bangladesh.
Similarly, the Skyla Shatyarti
individual, I have no idea who he was,
where he came from. I have no idea what
work he has allegedly done or not done.
But they gave him the Nobel Prize. So
maybe they are keeping him in store, in
reserve for future action. You know,
maybe they want to do something similar
in India like what happened in
Bangladesh,
regime change. And if that happens,
maybe they will make him the chief
adviser, right? if they if they
hypothetically succeed in such a
maneuver. So you know they they
cultivate this asset they give them
various prizes and designations and then
they put them in cold storage to be used
and activated later.
So maybe the deep state has plans for
him for the future.
Vidimar says HW CNN I N balconize
how can India [laughter]
how can India balconize Pakistan isn't
it powerful U Vasal
how can India balkconize Pakistan isn't
it
more powerful than India Pakistan is not
more powerful than India but it has the
backing of the world's most powerful
nation so how can India balconize
Pakistan
Well, you have to hit at the if you want
to bulcanize a nation, you decapitate
the leadership.
So the Pakistani command and control
structure is like a pyramid, right? At
the very top you have the Pakistani
chief marshall or whatever the hell what
Aimir right Aimir is currently the
dictator of Pakistan and below him we
have the army command and control
structure. Below them they have the
civilian government, the the police and
all that. That's the command and control
structure. If you want to de if you want
to balconize Pakistan, you to take out
the top leadership and make the entire
pyramid unsustainable.
So it's not enough to take out simply
aim. You have to take out the entire top
military structure of Pakistan and then
let the chaos in you know unfold. That's
what you do. And when that happens, when
there is a lack of decision-m for some
time, that's when you make your make
your moves militarily and take control
of various places and and you know that
way the the the pack of cards can fall.
So that's kind of how you do it.
You can also do a coup if you have the
resources for that in which case you
don't need a military operation but uh
when you have less money than the US
it's very hard to do that right Abaya no
question but all right thank you very
much thank you very much really
appreciate that
okay Ankita says what's your opinion on
recent GPS spoofing to misguide flights
new way of terrorism or warfare is there
any preventive technique to deal with
this situation I think I took it but
I'll take it again. So it it it could be
perhaps Pakistanis trying to
you know jam GPS signals over various
major airports
with the with the hope of maybe causing
some mishap. That's one possibility.
Second possibility is maybe the Indian
government is doing something
to prevent a Pakistani GPS. I mean
Pakistani attack, maybe missile attack,
maybe some other kind of attack and and
doing that while keeping the aircraft
safe possibly. And third is maybe the US
government is is messing up the GPS
signals over major Indian airports with
whatever objective they may have. So
if it is being done from outside India,
maybe from Pakistan, maybe the US, then
it is a very nasty thing to do. It's
kind of a terrorist kind of activity,
right? It's warfare by other means. It's
it's trying to cause a mishap, you know,
accident, air accident that is that is
very very bad. So what is the preventive
tech technique to deal with the
situation? The preventive technique is
for India to have a proper GPS
alternative, our own constellation of
satellites that give us the exact same
service or a better service than GPS.
That's the thing. So we have the Navic
system, but I'm not sure how operational
it is. I'm not sure and it is simply
confined to the Indian subcontinent
continent and slightly beyond it. The
American GPS system is global. The
Russian Gloon system is global global.
The Chinese BU or whatever system they
have that's also global. But our IRSS is
subcontinent-based. We have no ambition.
We are a country that lacks ambition.
The Chinese have been working on this
for like 10 15 years. At that time they
were not such a big economy but they
still had the ambition, right?
So we need to have our own alternative
to GPS. Same quality if not better
quality. That's what we need to have.
I'm not sure what the situation is with
the the the Navic U
system.
I would say that if it was fully
operational, then we could simply
seamlessly transition from GPS to Navic
in case there is spoofing. But clearly
that's not happened. So it looks like we
have no alternative right now to GPS.
Maybe Navic is used only by the
military. I'm not sure what the
situation is. But something like NAVIC
can be used for the military as well as
for civilian uh purposes in in in
different ways. That's what we should
have and that would be the preventive
technique. The diplomatic lens says do
you think during BJP government
occurrence of civil war is negligible
but in Congress it is inevitable since
now Hindus are more aware of oppression.
See, I do not discuss internal politics.
I do not discuss religious matters. I
discuss geopolitics. I stay away from
these matters. So, I will not take this
question. Congress, BJP, all that stuff.
I I will not go into this. I apologize.
But it's a policy. I don't discuss
internal matters in this in this on this
channel. I discuss geopolitics, history,
and science.
Mocha says government's plan to expand
medical visas for westerners will raise
health care costs and hurt Indians.
Please oppose this policy and tweet
about it. Okay, I will have to look into
the policy first of all, right? What is
the policy? Is there a new policy for
medical visas? If there's a policy for
medical visas, in a way it could be good
for the Indian economy. It doesn't have
to raise costs for all Indians, right?
Maybe you can have a certain set of
costs for see
in India we have tourism right to some
to some extent we have a tourism sector
in this country we have the potential to
be a tourism superpower but we are
tourism
also ran so in Indian tourism in the in
the Indian tourism sector if you want to
go to some historical site to some
museum or whatever then there are two
sets of fees if you go to a museum and
if you are an Indian citizen you may
have to pay Let's say 20 bucks, 20
rupees or 50 rupees, let's say. But if
you don't have an Indian passport, if
you're a foreigner, you have to pay 500
rupees double standards. So we can do
the same kind of double standards for
these medical visas. When westerners
come to India, charge higher costs, but
don't charge higher costs for Indians.
Uh so it depends on how the policy is is
is implemented.
I suppose the government can't can't
tell medical practitioners and
institutions what kind of fees they
should charge. Um so it it it's going to
have multiple considerations. So I'll
have to look into this and if it's
something that falls within my
my my domain then I could tweet about
that.
Tub says how to make this country get
its together. Sad.
Look, we have many issues, right?
Uh,
look, that's not a geopolitical
question, but how to get the country
together? We need better leadership. I'm
not saying we have bad leadership right
now. We have potentially the best
leadership we've ever had since 1947.
But still, there are so many issues that
need to be looked into. One thing we
need to do is get rid of all the
Bangladeshes, Rohingya, Pakistanis,
cookies, get them out of the country,
all foreigners out. That's number one.
Number two, whatever alleged corruption
may or may not exist, please deal with
that. That itself will make the country
get its together.
Neil Shaw says, "All I hear everywhere
is all problems India has and how we
don't see any significant progress being
made towards solving them. But on the
other hand, I also hear if we just
survive the next 20 years, we would be
hard to mess with."
So every country has problems,
right?
Even the US has tremendous problems.
One problem in the US, every citizen in
the US has access to drugs. Drugs are
available on each every street corner.
Every street corner has drug dealers.
Why isn't that a gigantic problem for
the US, right? And then all the other
stuff that so every country has
problems. Now there are people in India
who only want to focus on the problems.
There is significant progress in India.
India is unrecognizable
compared to 2014.
Okay. The problems we had in 2014, a lot
of those problems no longer exist.
But now we are more ambitious because of
the progress that's happened, the growth
that's happened since 2014. And that's
why we want more the other problems to
go away. So Indians are now more
impatient, more ambitious.
And that's why you kind of see a lot of
problems. And today we have social
media. We have free speech today in
2025. Did we have actual free speech in
2014? Could Indians speak openly the way
they speak today in 2014? Ask yourself
these things. So that's why you
apparently see more problems. But the
problems were always there and many of
the problems have been solved. A lot of
the poverty has been eradicated in the
past 10 11 years. A lot of things have
happened. And so that's that is one
thing. And secondly, it's true if India
gets its, you know, just just keeps its
head its head down, avoids any major
military confrontation and keeps growing
its economy at even 5 6 7% per year for
the next 20 years, India is going to be
a totally different beast in 20 years.
You think India is going to be really
hard to mess with if we can just keep on
the right track for the next 20 years.
No question about it. Despite all the
problems India has, India India will
still be hard to mess with if we stay on
the on the right track for 20 years. So
there is no question about it. That is
completely correct.
Pratt Dhana says looks like
is done and is it significant? I am not
right now keeping track of the minute
developments in the Ukraine war. What's
happened in Kovsk? Let's see. Is it
significant? Look. Uh, let me see. What
has happened in Pokrosovsk?
Whoops. What is that? Why is Navik
there?
Pokovsk. What happened? Bakubot. Bakmod
is an old story. Pokarovsk
break out near Pokovsk. 30 killed Russia
hits with fighting intensifies in
Pokarovsk. Did Russia Russian milers
claim the village had been completely
captured which was confirmed on 3rd
September? Okay, we are in what today is
16th of November. So the Russians
captured a village. Is it significant?
Look, it will be significant when they
capture Kiev. All these little half a
kilometer here, half a kilometer there.
I don't I don't even keep track of this
anymore. It doesn't matter. So [snorts]
yeah.
Yeah, it doesn't really from my
perspective it's not significant. There
are all these little military observers
who keep on looking at every half
kilometer of what's happening this half
kilometer what is happening there. They
will keep on it will keep them keep
giving them content and something to
talk about. From my perspective from
grand strategy perspective it makes no
difference. Yeah, my perspective is very
clear. Russia is going to prevail in
this conflict conflict whenever it does
prevail. Whether it will happen in the
next six weeks or next six years that is
that remains to be seen that remains it
will depend on what Mr. Putin wants to
do and how he wants to do things. But
one village being captured I I'm not
concerned.
AKS BA says Maduro offering 300 billion
barrels of oil to the US. Okay, this see
the the thing is
I don't I am not a news surfer. I'm not
complaining. Okay, I'm I'm just saying
I'm just explaining the way I analyze
things. I am not a news surfer. I don't
keep track of what's happening every 1
hour or every one day. I may know what
happened last week. If you try and keep
track of exactly what's happening at the
at the latest moment, then you will be
overwhelmed with information and you
will not be able to process it properly.
The less you watch the news, the better
informed you are. That is my
philosophy.
The less you consume, the more informed
you are. So what I do is I look at what
happened. What are the major major
events that happened in the last week?
Then I'll do that one week from now. I
will not keep track of what's happening
every minute. So I'm not aware of this
offer that Maduro has made. If he has
made it, good. Maduro must be desperate
because the US is putting together an
invasion force in the Caribbean in the
region near around Venezuela. A couple
of aircraft carriers and uh
uh maybe an invasion force on the
islands in the region. So it looks like
the US is preparing for a proper
invasion of Venezuela. So maybe Maduro
is desperate and he knows that Vladimir
Putin from all far away in Russia can't
help him. So maybe he's trying to
find some some way out of the situation
that he is facing. In case he has made
this offer, I am not aware of it.
Anamalai s says you just said this. You
just said this. In 50 years, India
mostly won't even be a Hindu or secular
nation. My question is why did you say
that or think that? How many Indians
practice Hinduism today? Uh first of
all, what's the percentage of non-Hindus
in India today? According to the 2011
outdated census what about 80% are
Hindus there is 2011 we don't even have
a recent census
um there is industrial scale conversion
activities happening in India right
industrial scale mass conversions
happening in India every day thousands
of Indians are converted to other
religions every day how many are
converted to Hinduism
almost nobody right how many churches
are being built in India
New churches we can see tons of them
cropping up everywhere. How many new
temples have been built? Nothing. How
many Hindus who are still Hindus
practice actually practice Hinduism? How
many are proud of being Hindus? Very few
today, especially in cities. If you look
at the names that people give to their
children, do you see Hindu names?
Do you see the Indian government doing
anything to support Hinduism?
Yeah.
So that's why I say this.
Dravidian says is
fr
truly a US wasal and TR also bought
S400.
Are France and and Turkey really
American and Turkey also bought S400?
France
is a member of the EU. France is a
member of NATO and if you understand
what sovereignty is and how it works,
you will see that both are vasals of the
US. But France is the one member of the
EU and NATO that has a quasi independent
foreign policy and a completely
independent nuclear deterrent. But it
still is a US vasal because it is not
territorially sovereign. It is not
economically sovereign. It doesn't have
its own currency. Its borders are open
and so much more. So it's not a
sovereign nation. Turkey, it's a member
of NATO. It has American troops on its
soil. It has American nuclear weapons on
its soil.
It's not a sovereign nation.
If it's a member of NATO, there are
times during which parts of its military
come under foreign command. Do you call
that sovereignty?
Yeah. It bought the S400. got some kind
of preferential treatment from the US
but it but in response it was denied the
F-35 which was was okay with Turkey.
Turkey also is a Wasal. Nagarand the
Shenoi is a new member. Thank you very
much Nagaranj. Really appreciate that.
And Devil X537 is also a new member.
Thank you very much Devil XG. I really
appreciate you as well. Thank you very
much both of you.
Spade says I have composed Chavda
Chalisa. Bless us. [laughter]
It's very funny. Yes.
All right. All right. All right.
6P70 Delta says, "Which is more likely
to happen in your opinion? Democracy in
Russia or dictatorship in India? Whose
expiry date will come earlier, Ukraine
or Pakistan?" Well, well, well, well.
Democracy in Russia or dictatorship in
India? Which is more likely to happen?
Dictatorship in India? I don't see it.
happening do I democracy in Russia
I think democracy in Russia is more
likely than dictatorship in India why
because we don't know what happens after
Mr. Putin leaves power so Mr. Putin is
in his 70s. Let's say he has a decade
more in power. Okay? But eventually he's
going to have to step down one way or
the other.
So when he steps down, the succession is
the make or break point for the
continuity of Russia. If the person who
comes to power after Mr. Putin is
capable just like Mr. Putin, things
continue and dictatorship continues. If
you want to call what currently exists
as dictatorship in Russia. But if the
person is a weak person then you will
have the introduction of US style
democracy in Russia. I think that is
more likely to happen in Russia compared
to dictatorship being introduced in
India because India is a nation that
worships some vidan
and what uh parliament
so it's it's less likely to happen in
India. Uh whose expiry date will come
earlier Ukraine or Pakistan?
probably Ukraine.
I hope I'm completely wrong about that,
but probably Ukraine.
Siddhart Bilad says, "Good evening."
Good evening to you, sir. Could you
enlighten us on our nuclear capabilities
given that we have only carried out a
single nuclear test and claims that it
was subcritical. We have carried out two
sets of nuclear tests. One was 1974,
the second was 1998. And there have been
some claims by some individuals that one
of the one of the nuclear devices
fizzled.
So what's a fizzle? See a fizzle means
not all of the file material was
consumed in that nuclear explosion.
That's what a fizzle means. Which means
that the
that the shaping or whatever the
geometry was not perfect. So that's why
you conduct multiple tests. The
Americans when they conducted various
tests there were some tests that fizzled
and some tests that had way more output
than what was expected. Maybe they were
expect expecting 10 megat tons but it
gave you 17 megatons. Woo too much too
much. So you have to fine-tune the
parameters the geometry you know the
lens the lensing action and all that
within the nuclear device. You have an
initial
explosion that is a chemical explosion
that pushes the various nuclear file
material components together and then if
it's a thermonuclear device then the
initial fish fision reaction has to
ignite completely. It should consume all
of the file material and it should then
implo create an implosion which ignites
a secondary fusion reaction and all the
fusion material berilium dutium whatever
it is should ignite completely and that
gives you this massive thermonuclear
explosion. So [clears throat] you need a
sign you need a specific geometry you
need all the components to be shaped in
specific ways and they have to come
together in specific ways and all that.
It's pretty it's it's pretty uh complex.
It's kind of
a marriage between engineering and art,
you know,
producing designing nuclear
weapons.
Um and that's why it's possible that
when you test a nuclear weapon the first
time, it may not work properly. Maybe
all of the nuclear material was not
consumed in the reaction and it it
fizzled. So instead of giving you a 50
kiloton
um you know output maybe it gave you a
20 kiloton output that sort of thing
that's kind of maybe 10 kilotons or
whatever. So that's a fizzle. Now some
people have claimed that one of the
Indian maybe the Indian thermonuclear
device fizzled. So a thermonuclear
device is a three-stage
reaction. The first initial chemical
explosion which with with chemical
explosions then a second fish reaction
fish explosion which gives rise to an
implosion situation which gives rise to
the fusion reaction and explosion. So
that is more likely to fizzle than a
standard fishing device. So um what is
my opinion about this? I have no idea. I
wasn't present there. I have not seen
the data and I don't know what happened.
My point is the s simplest way forward
is to do do a few more tests.
That's it.
In case there was a fizzle obviously
then you would come to know because you
know what the output is and then you can
you know tweak the design a little bit
and then test a few more times to ensure
that it functions functions properly.
But the problem is you can't test
because there is a global moratorium on
testing. So that's why you have to do
subcritical tests
which are which is the test tests only
with a chemical explosive without using
actual file material or you can do
computer simulations or whatever but
that is not the ideal way to do things.
The ideal way is to test a few times in
real life. So that's all I can say. I
don't know if there was a fizzle of any
kind if there was any subcritical event.
Can't say
ISBA says thoughts on 7,000 Russian
deaths in the past week. I have no
thoughts about that. Who has made this
claim? The West, right? The West has
been claiming what that Putin was dying.
The West has been claiming since 2022
that Russia has been losing. They are
losing Bakmod. They are losing
everything. They've lost 3 million
lives. Ukraine is winning. Putin has
cancer. Putin has this. They have been
making all kinds of claims over and over
again. All those claims have turned out
to be lies. And still Indians believe
this. I don't believe any of this
nonsense. I don't believe Western
propaganda. I don't even believe Russian
propaganda. I look at the lines on the
map. Where is the Russian advance right
now? That's all I care about. That's the
only hard facts I have. Everything else
is propaganda. So, I I I don't care. I I
have no thoughts about this. UMX says,
um, current Indians obsessed with actual
third rate Bollywood content which is
completely horrible and shows false
history of India. I don't watch
Bollywood. I gave up on Bollywood a long
time ago. I used to like movies from the
19 from the 1900s before
I would say before the mid 1970s. Movies
before that those were good. The music
was good. The songs were good. The
stories were pretty s pretty simple,
pretty genuine, wholesome. After that,
all kinds of ghastly stuff started being
introduced into Bollywood. And uh there
there have been a few good movies here
and there. But overall, I I simply have
no interest left in Bollywood movies
anymore. I am a huge movie fan, okay? I
love movies.
You give me the opportunity, I'll watch
two movies a week on the big screen.
I'll pay good money to do that if the
movies are good. I can't remember the
last time I went to watch a movie
because even the Hollywood movies are
garbage now.
So sad. But yes, Indians, they're
obsessed with all this Bollywood masala
movies and all this OTT platform uh what
TV series or whatever it is. I can't
stand any of that. I'm sure there are
some hidden gems there that I must be
missing but I I simply don't watch
anymore.
Okay. AKS Baga says thoughts on US
bomber in Bangalore
B1 was it?
I have seen a few things. I travel on
and off to various cities. I have seen
interesting things.
Maybe Bangalore, maybe Delhi. Yeah, I
I'm not sure why it was here or why it I
don't know if it is still there or if it
is gone. If it has left
a B1B, right? B1 or whatever it was. B1B
bomber. I'm not sure why it was here.
Are they trying to sell a few of those
to us? I would say we should not buy
American military hardware. We should
not because that those things come with
kill switches and back doors and whatnot
and that versalizes us if we buy those
things. I would say we should not buy
it. So maybe the Americans are trying to
you know sell the bomber to us or maybe
they've sent a few generals to talk to
us for some reason. I have no idea. It's
all complete wild speculation at this
point in time. But yes, I did I did
notice that. I did notice it but I don't
know what what it's for. Ritwick says
Arunachal Pradesh is my favorite state
and I visited it as a tourist. I suggest
you to visit Tawang the best place. I
saw you standing near Axai. You saw me
there. I was on the on the LC with Axai
Chin. I've been there a couple of times
at least multiple times. Yeah. But did
you see me there or did you see a video
of me there? Because I must have taken
videos there or photographs. If you did
see me with your own eyes, you could
have come and said hi. Anyway, uh yeah.
So I haven't been to Arunachal Pradesh
thus far. I may know some people there.
I would love to visit Tawang for sure.
Yeah. So thank you very much for the
suggestion for the recommendation and I
shall make it a point to visit Tawang
hopefully soon.
Parto Jani says do we really have legs
on Kandahar air base? How? I don't know.
There's all kinds of speculation in
social media.
general
we have what Indian
Indian transport aircraft has landed in
Ganda. I have no idea how much of this
is true, how much of this is not. The
government of India has said no such
thing. There are all these YouTube
channels that that whose entire game is
speculation and hyperbolic claims to get
views. I am not that sort of person. I
I'm going to be very realistic. I have
no idea what's happening in Kandahar.
Okay, Kandahar Air Base. It is a very
major air base. It's it's probably the
biggest air base in the subcontinent
and the [snorts] Americans want it. But
the Taliban doesn't want the US to have
it. But the Taliban is also not crazy,
right? If they offer it to India, the
Americans will get really, really upset.
So, I'm not sure what the situation is.
Would I want India to have legs boots on
the ground in Kandahar? I would be very
pleased if that happens.
I would be very pleased if India gets to
operate that air base to safeguard
Afghanistan as well as deal with
Pakistan.
Yeah, that will be that'll be great from
my opinion from my perspective. But is
that in the process of happening? I
don't know. I have no evidence. I have
no data. So can't say. 6P70 Delta says
why are Indians going gaga over
Tajakistan air base? Don't they
understand that our fighter fleet is
dwindling and transport transport fleet
is aging? We can't sustain.
Um I have no idea. There there are
stories that India is no longer
operating an air base in Tajakistan
whether it is a or far I'm not sure
which and I would say it's no big deal.
Look in the 21st century fighter planes
don't even matter that much anymore.
Do you understand why everything is
today a game of missiles?
Why would you put a fighter plane and a
highly trained pilot in the line of fire
when you can do everything you want to
do with long-range missiles or or
medium-range missiles? Extraordinarily
precise missiles that we have. We have
missiles that are so precise that we can
fly them through a window in some part
of Pakistan. A specific window we can
tell them to fly through. So why do we
need fighter planes to do that work? We
can use fighter planes to do a a
different role to play a different role
after the enemy has been sanitized and
their air defenses have been suppressed.
[clears throat] So yeah, our fighter
fleet is is dwindling. We need more
fighter planes. No question.
And right now as a stock gap measure we
have to we are forced to rely on
missiles more which may not be a bad
thing but it means that we need to have
significant supplies of missiles
stockpiles of missiles. Uh so that's the
situation.
Uh we certainly need to do something
about our military capabilities. We are
good in the area of missiles but fighter
planes transport aircraft maybe
strategic bombers we don't have any of
those. There's a lot that we need to do
and right now the situation is that
Pakistan almost has parity with us when
it comes to fighter planes. I mean we
are a nation with almost five $5
trillion GDP. Pakistan is nothing
compared to us but they almost have
parity with us. Shameful that we have
allowed ourselves to be in this
situation. Yeah. Well, what can I say?
Pratadana says YouTube subs and views
numbers are 100% fake. Um, very
possible, [laughter]
very possible. Uh, you can gain that if
you are behind the scenes, not as a
YouTuber, but as an admin. I'm sure.
Yeah.
Devil X537 says, "YouTube might not be
your fan, but I'm a super fan. Thank you
so much. Also, please do give us some
hope for the future of India as most of
the problems we facing seem impossible
to pass, and all we hear is critique."
Look, I'll tell you what. Like I've said
before, I've said this many times, we
have problems like every nation has
problems. Maybe some of the problems are
bad and pretty strong, pretty big. But
let me tell you this,
if we continue on the right path for 20
years,
if we keep growing our economy just 5,
6, 7% a year, let's say 6% for 20 years,
we're going to be a completely different
beast. In 20 years, nobody's going to be
able to
mess with us. Let's use that word, mess
with us. I had a different word in mind.
Okay,
the next 20 years are are going to be a
tough climb ahead. But that's the fun in
life. Who wants to have an easy life?
You want to have adventure? You want to
have big challenges. So, we have to all
work together in that in whichever way
we can contribute. next 20 years if we
if we stay on the right path
nobody will be able to mess with us
despite whatever problems we may be
facing that is the truth
so there will be people who will try to
discourage you with this that etc I'll
not comment about those things but the
truth is that we are just 20 years away
from from completely
uh rising above the little problems that
that drag us on in 20 years Pakistan
won't even matter
and China will will see us very
differently so will the US if we stay on
track so that is the deal there is I am
a very optimistic person and this is not
blind optimism this is just a factual
assessment of how things stand today
that's what we need to do
so uh thank you very much sir for being
a super fan I really appreciate that and
all all of you thank you [laughter]
excuse Excuse [clears throat]
me.
Pratam Sony says, "Watching you since
2019. One session raising your
standards." Maybe we should have that.
Yeah, maybe we can have that.
Maybe I can do one session ask in which
we discuss personal development, raising
your standards, all that. Maybe I can do
that. Thank you for the recommendation.
Thank you very much.
Dir 63 says, "Aliens will unite
humanity. We need aliens.
Maybe we need aliens. But the question
is if let's say tomorrow we face
a genuine alien threat. Sure, we will
have to unite. But we will need
leadership. We can't unite under 53
different leaders, right? We will need
one leader. The question is who's going
to be the leader? The answer is the most
powerful country will be the leader.
Who's the most powerful country?
It's the US. So, we're going to have to
go under US leadership.
[laughter] Kind of like a deal with the
devil, right?
Okay. Devil X537 says, "Also, sir,
please set up some other ways to donate
to you [clears throat] where you get
more money than sh than sharing it with
these American companies." Okay.
Um,
yeah, I could do that. I I could do this
actually, you know. Um, yeah. I I no
longer do this these days, but I could
simply put up a QR code. I used to have
a QR code somewhere. Where is that? Give
me a second. Give me a second. Okay.
Here is a QR code. I have not been doing
this for a while, right? So, if Yeah.
This way there will be no sharing with
an American company. There we have it.
All right. [laughter] Yeah. Okay. Next
time I I'll keep this QR code up. I have
been putting up the Ask a Bijit logo
over there. So, uh, thank you for
reminding me of this. Yeah. So anybody
who wants to support the channel please
free feel free to do that but um even if
you don't I'm perfectly happy. So so
thank you sir Deville X I appreciate you
very much. Thank you. Spade says I agree
with Devil X 537J Chow. [laughter]
Thank you very much. Thank you very
much.
Ajinka Pawar says any comment on Delhi
blast India's next move. I took multiple
questions about that. Um
what how do I see this? It's obviously
an act of terrorism. It's an act of
terrorism by Indian citizens, doctors,
well-educated people which kind of tells
you that education makes no difference.
Education makes no difference. It
doesn't prevent people from being
terrorists, from becoming terrorists.
Something else makes them terrorists
whatever it may be. So it was highly
educated professional doctors, Indian
citizens who are involved in this and
they had some connections with Kashmir
Valley based terrorists and there may or
may not be uh some kind of Pakistani
connection. The problem is that these
are Indian citizens who have done this.
So if we make a move on Pakistan, the
world will accuse India of being a
wararmonger. And that is the conundrum
we are facing. You see that's the
conundrum we are facing. India's next
move,
India will have to crack down on
internal potential terrorists. India
will have to be very vigilant in
uncovering all these terrorist uh
networks which may or may not exist. My
my appeal to the government of India is
please deport the Bangladeshes,
Rohingyas, Pakistanis, cookies, whoever
may be there on Indian territory. In
2014, the government of India had said
in parliament that with there are 50
million Bangladeshes in India in 2014.
By now the number may possibly have
doubled 100 million. What are we doing?
You want less terrorism, get rid of
these people. India's next move right
now, I don't see a war with Pakistan at
this point in time. That's what I can
say. I I I may be wrong and maybe I hope
I'm wrong, but I don't see that
happening right now.
Dilx537 says, "Hope you get lots of
publicity to and get to 10 million subs
one day." Well, thank you very much,
sir. Thank you very much. I really
appreciate that. I really appreciate
your support
and your contribution. Thank you so
much.
6P70 Delta says, "If the US ever
collapses, will it be more violent than
USSR's collapse? Considering the
polarization, hatred and amount of guns
in civilian hands.
considering the the amount of guns in
civil civilian hands and if you look at
the nature of the society where there is
you know it seems to be a high trust
society but it's also very tribal
territorial society
king of the castle kind of behavior you
trespass into my property I have the
right to shoot you sort of you know
attitude people have
[clears throat]
so if there is a collapse in the US
someday in the future It's going to be
pretty violent. It's going to be like
one of those zombie movies or something.
It's going to be like that. I I hope it
doesn't happen like that. Okay. I I hold
no ill will towards the people who live
there. But yeah, it's it's a it's kind
of a volcano waiting to erupt. The
number of guns you have in the US. More
guns than citizens. My goodness. Yeah.
RDRA says 1951 India's share 14% 18%
3361 million 1.5 billion 2.5 billion 8.2
2 billion natural I'm sorry
1951 India's global share 14% to 18% to
361 million 1.5 billion 2.5 billion 8.2
2 billion natural growth. Uh are you
talking about GDP? Are you talking about
population? Obviously, it'll be GDP
because we don't have 2.5 billion
people. Um I'm not exactly sure what
you're saying, but you're saying
something nice and optimistic. So, I
appreciate that, sir. I appreciate that.
Uh Arin Raj says, "Can you explain
India's linguistic history, how language
families work and whether LLMs can aid
the study of ancient languages like
you can ask this question in a history
episode, sir.
I'm discussing geopolitics today and
this is a pretty pretty complex question
you've asked I can't answer that in the
next two three minutes
to explain in brief India's linguistic
history goes back at least 10,000 years
language families how they work well
that's that I can't explain right now
llms can can they aid the study of
ancient languages like Sanskrit they
certainly can yeah okay Pratip Kumar Roy
says about sir in West Bengal I have no
idea that is an internal matter of India
I discuss geopolitics so I can't say
I've heard that there is something going
which is going to happen I have not
looked into it so I won't be able to
comment about that and anyway I don't
look into these internal developments
and I don't discuss them anyway right
Sagacharan says how will Trump crypto
interests shape geopolitics so Trump is
investing in Pakistan's cryptocurrency
sector which did not exist until Trump
decided to invest in it
um and Trump has actually said this in I
think in the White House or wherever he
said it that maybe we will put all our
debt into cryptocurrency and and and
make it disappear that way.
So I would say that you should stay away
from cryptocurrency.
Um maybe
it [clears throat] is something that may
give you profits in the short term but
long term it's going to be a disaster.
It is simply a geopolitical tool to get
rid of the debt to deflate the debt out
of existence.
And nations like India should be very
careful about the cryptocurrency sector.
We should not put major resources into
that.
Divor Singh says why did Trump not end
up taking Greenland in Canada? Well,
Trump is all about hype, right? Trump is
all about he has cultivated this image
of unpredictability.
He makes a statement a minute and 90% of
the statements he makes, he doesn't mean
them. He's trying to throw people off
track. He's trying to throw keep people
off balance and he's perfectly okay with
people regarding him as a liar because
he does lie all the time. So it was all
about creating hype and maybe making a
move somewhere else. So it doesn't look
like he's going to take Greenland and
Canada. But he looked like he was
serious about Greenland at least, wasn't
he? Because he sent his son to Greenland
and uh he proposed buying the entire
territory from Denmark. So maybe that
may still be on the cards and it may
still happen perhaps in the future maybe
before he demits office. But Canada
probably is something that that's more
of a tongue-in-cheek thing you know
calling the prime minister of Canada the
governor of of the great state of
Canada. So about some things he is
definitely not serious. Maybe maybe he
still may be serious about Greenland.
Ivan says please throw some light on May
and his contribution to the to to India
because what kind of geopolitics was at
the time for a nation like Maywar? You
are very smart. You've thrown the word
geopolitics in there into a historical
question. Look, I am not I am not an
expert in May. I I can't say can't say
because I haven't studied the history of
mir.
Um definitely a lot of great people came
from the region from from the overall
Rajasthan region may marad and so all
that but u yeah I I won't be able to
answer the question because I haven't
studied the history of Maywar in depth
in in depth and you won't have
geopolitics emerging from because it was
a subset of the subcontinent right
Nikil Bansali says if not democracy
which system do you think works
Specifically from the perspective of
sustaining highquality leadership,
democracy seems to be failing us. Look,
all you have to do to answer this
question is look back at history. You
don't have to look back at world
history. Look back at the history of
your own culture, of your own
civilization. Look back at the history
of India. Look back at the history of
India the past 2 and a half thousand
years. Ask yourself when were the times
in the past 2 and a half thousand years
where India was doing great. I'll tell
you the Morian Empire that period of
time the Kushan Empire fantastic India
was a superpower during the Kushan
period then the Gupta period major power
India right we took Bahalik and so much
more central Asia parts of central Asia
so Gupta period Gupta empire powerful
brilliant tremendous prosperity and
wealth then we have the Chola period
that's again an imperial period imperial
period. Then you have the Marata period
in which we reconquer India and
reestablish Hinduisa. So these are the
times when India did brilliantly.
We also had the Satwahana period which
was an empire in the Dean region
southern India brilliant time of
tremendous prosperity. So all of these
periods of time you had empires which
are dictatorships.
That's your what what what your own
history tells you
and that's that is the answer.
But [clears throat] but these were not
Saddam Hussein type of dictatorships.
These were dharmic dictatorships.
Understand that. 6P70 Delta says
allegedly in 2013 14 US citizens bought
the same number of kalash because as the
entire Russian law enforcement and
military. Okay, I'm not aware of this
statistic, but it's a very interesting
thing if it's true. See, the Kalashnikov
the Kalashnikov is is
the greatest
product ever built perhaps.
You know,
zero marketing was done for the
Kalashnikov for the AK-47. Zero
marketing.
But it became the most popular
small arms weapon globally in global in
in world history only through word of
mouth. It works in every condition. It
is it is so easy that even like 12 year
olds can use it and actually that's
happened in places like Africa and where
you have child soldiers. Horrible
horrible absolutely horrible but 12 year
old kids can use the kalashnikov. You
can learn how to use it in like 3
minutes.
That's how simple it is, but it is super
reliable. And I mean, what can I say?
It's it's so popular, right? It's
incredibly popular because it's the best
weapon ever built. And then you've had
the Automat Kalashnikov 57. And then you
have 104 or whatever, which are
spin-offs of the original 47 version,
but the 407 version is the gold
standard. It's still the best weapon
ever. So, if [laughter] if this is the
case, then I'm not surprised at all.
VSVS24000
says I wanted to say that people confuse
real GDP uh 6.7 6 to 7% inflation
adjusted with nominal GDP which is 9 to
9 to 10%. India's 4 trillion GDP is
nominal. You can't apply real growth to
nominal GDP. At 9% nominal for 20 years
we hit 20 to 30 trillion. Real is for
economists. All right. I will have to
look into this. I am not an expert in
economics. Uh so once again let me
reexamine what you're saying. People
confuse real GDP which is 6 to 7%
inflation adjusted with nominal GDP
which is 9 to 10% which is not inflation
adjusted. Okay. So India's 4 trillion
GDP is nominal. It's not real. Okay. You
can't apply real growth to nominal GDP.
at 9% nominal for 20 years. We hit 20 to
25 to 30 trillion. Real is for
economists. Okay. Noted, sir. Thank you.
Thank you. Interesting. We'll have to
look into that in more detail.
And that brings us to the end of the
questions in the super chat. I think I
have covered them all. All right. How
much time has it? Okay. It's been 2
hours 44 45 minutes, which is a long
long time. Okay. Okay. Do we have any
more super? Okay, there's one more super
chat. Let me take that as well. The
rational reporter says, "What should
what would India's political, economic,
social future look like? If we organized
our society based on ancient Indian
philosophy, Sanatan Jane Buddhist kind
of Indian renaissance then on western
philosophy. What would India's
political, economic and social future
look like? Well, India would be a more
cohesive, more peaceful society for
sure.
India would be a better organized
society. India would have probably zero
corruption,
uh better political stability,
a better economy, uh more prosperity,
more wealth
and uh yeah, that's how it would be. But
it would be it would take time to
transition to that kind of society
because right now we are a very weird
mixed up colonized society. So to
transition to that thing would take
maybe a few decades. But yeah, in the
long term it would be good because that
that is the real nature of our society
and that's how it actually should be
organized. So yeah, it would be good if
that happens. Nikl Bali says I think
Indian kings and royalty were as
responsible as British and Mgles for
ruling us as long as they did. They were
oppressive Gandhi family types two lakh
ruling 100 crores. I'll tell you
something. I'll tell you something Nicl
Bali G our experience with Indian kings
and royalty is the princely states right
the princely states
these princely states they came into
existence
in the 19th century
the princely states that we are familiar
with are the princely states that were
allowed to continue to exist by the
British after 1857
in 1857 you had Indian kings who fought
the British and unfortunately they all
lost eventually and they were all wiped
out. The entire families were wiped out
and then some distant relation would be
would be discovered and placed as a
puppet king. So after 1857 after we lost
that war of independence, every single
princely state king who was allowed to
keep ruling
nominally was a British vasal.
Some of them were genuinely good people.
They said that you know instead of dying
out let us
cooperate with the British but serve our
people in some way in whatever way we
can. Some of them were good but many of
them
they owed their title as king to the
generosity of the British. So they
served the British. Many of them many of
these so-called princely states the
so-called kings were collaborators with
the British
collaborating they were collaborating
with the foreign occupier of India. So
that is our experience of these kings.
But we have forgotten the kings who
fought the British and died for us. We
have fought all those kings who fought
the Turks for 500 years and died.
So you have to look at history from
different lenses. If you look at history
from a 50-year lens, you will see a
certain picture. If you look at history
from a 200year lens, you will see a
different picture. If you see if you
look at history from a 2 and a half
thousand year lens, you will see a
totally different picture. So let us
have different perspectives. Let us let
us have a broader horizon. Let us not be
narrow-minded and see only a certain
thing part of history and then base all
our judgments based on what we have seen
from that narrow part of part of
history. That's what I would urge
everybody to do. Please develop a
broader set of horizons
and don't come to these judgments based
on based on the belief that you
understand everything. I don't
understand everything. I still try to
learn every single day something new. So
let's let's not be under the delusion
that we understand the world. There is a
lot that we don't know. Let's have an
open mind and let us not be so
self-loathing.
Let us not have this inferiority complex
that our people were all bad. All right.
That's what I would request all of you
to do.
Okay. Okay. Sahil Singh says, "Bless me,
sir, for my interview on the 27th."
Well, all the best, Sahil. All the best.
You have my Well, I am, who am I to
bless? But you have I wish you the best.
You have my best wishes. Do well and
achieve whatever you want to achieve.
All the best. All right. 6P70 Delta
said, "I meant the number of guns in the
hands of US citizens." I think that's
exactly what I meant.
There are more guns than citizens in the
US.
So yeah, if you look at the number of
guns in the hands of US citizens, it's a
terrifying number. And if the US
descends into political instability, it
could lead to something very disastrous.
I hope it doesn't happen. All right,
that brings me to the end of today's
live stream. I have dealt with all the
questions from the super chat and we
have crossed 2 hours 49 minutes. We are
almost at 2 hours 50 minutes. So let us
now end this live stream. Thank you very
much everybody for the questions. I
really appreciate that. I I think we
covered a lot of different topics
and I
yeah I look forward to seeing you all
next week in next week's live streams.
Until there until then please keep
learning. Keep an open open mind. Don't
believe you understand everything. I
don't understand everything. I there's a
lot I don't understand. So please keep
learning. Keep asking questions and keep
raising your standards. Take care
everyone. I'll see you in the next one.
Bye-bye.